Keep the tape going until it's built all the way to the starting point by
Keep the tape going until it's built all the way to the starting point by
finish thebarsr that had been formatted before.
finish thebarsr that had been formatted before.
Then dig some more, and build in some really nice things that are ready earned.
Then dig some more, and build in some really nice things that are ready earned.
Those float doors will create some similar architecture to this little corner.
Those float doors will create some similar architecture to this little corner.
I used to work on p Putin's writers by six hundred when the lights lights went out.
I used to work on p Putin's writers by six hundred when the lights lights went out.
Now the talent activated will help the comments that more people were buying,
Now the talent activated will help the comments that more people were buying,
Now Āijhāmāsāka must be built in WWanjatana
Now Āijhāmāsāka jāgrade ē WWanjātanā
Āijhāmāsaka should be created in WWanjatana
Āijhāmāsāka jāgrade ē WWanjātanā
Good evening, gentlemen, hello, everyone
各位先生 大家晚安 大家好
It's great to have so many people listening to us today
今天很高興能夠有這麼多人來聽我們
A speech by Hong Sang-sung, a specific researcher
洪尚成特定研究員的一個演講
First let me briefly introduce his background
首先我來簡單介紹一下他的背景
Shang Chenghe is actually from Qigu Township, Tainan County
尚成他實際上是台南縣七谷鄉
A child who grew up in the countryside
鄉下長大的一個小孩子
But he didn't study well
但是他很沒念書
He later entered the Chemistry Department of Qingda University
他後來進了青大化學系
After 1 month at a very young age
1月以後以很年輕的年紀
Received a Ph.D. from Qingda University before the age of 30
還不滿30歲就拿到了青大的博士學位
very impressive
很了不起
He is Professor Liao Juncheng of Qingda University
他是青大廖俊成教授
Also a beneficiary student of Professor Guan Bijun
還有關比軍教授的得益門生
After he got his Ph.D.
他拿到博士學位以後
Received the Ministry of Education's postdoctoral study abroad scholarship
拿到教育部博士後的研究留學的獎金
Sweeps and Pengshui in the United States, our Zhongnanjun Institute
到美國的Sweeps跟鵬水我們中南俊院
The current President of the Hong Kong Council
現在的洪請會議院長
Three years of postdoctoral research
在三年的博士後的研究
Then when he comes back
那他回過以後
Consistently excellent research performance
一直有很傑出的研究的表現
upper he actually
上層他實際上
The main focus of his research
他最主要研究的重點
It is in the part of Tang Chemistry and Tang Biology
就是在唐化學跟唐生物學的部分
Then he is in these special
那他在這一些特別是
on the cell membrane
細胞膜上面的
The analysis of these bullets
這些彈彈百質的分析
quite accomplished
相當有成就
We published his reading in
他的念文我們發表在
our people in science
我們在科學界的人
If there is an article published in a natural journal
如果說有一篇在自然期刊發表
that's a shame
那是很表不起的事情
that upper he has this one
那上層他有這一個
Nature
Nature
And Nature Chemistry
還有Nature Chemistry
is Nature Journal
就是自然期刊
Journal of Natural Chemistry
自然化學期刊
and the Journal of the American Chemical Society
以及美國化學學會期刊的
This very important chanting
這個很重要的這個念文
Of course his research is very good
當然他的研究有很好的表現
Of course it's the winning document
當然就是得獎文書
The public health label I just told him about
我剛才跟他講到的公衛標明
he got this congressional
他得到了這個國會會的
Academic Awards of the Ministry of Education
傑出獎教育部的學術獎
And our former dean
還有我們前院長
Brilliant talent machine driven
推動的傑出人才機器
Distinguished Talent Award
經會的傑出人才獎
And won the TECO Award
並且得到了東元獎
There is also the Contribution Award for Li Tiande's medical achievements
還有李天德的醫療成就的貢獻獎
So in terms of research
所以在研究方面
The upper level is quite outstanding
上層是相當的傑出
he got it very young
他很年輕就得了
This is the chairperson of the Congress
這個套一句國會會主委
Zhu Jingyi's words
朱靜一的話
It is said that the medals filled with film on the body are like this
說身上灌膜的勳章這樣
but one important thing
但是很重要的一件事情
In addition to doing a good job in his research
他除了研究做得很好以外
He is also enthusiastic about teaching
他在教學方面也很熱心
He interacts well with students
他學生的互動很好
So he got Tsinghua University
所以他拿到了清華大學的
this outstanding teacher
這個傑出的教師
quite difficult
相當的不容易
So we specially invite him to give a speech to you today.
所以我們今天特別請他來跟大家演講
because he is a good speaker
因為他是一個很好的講者
He will introduce to you today
他今天要跟大家介紹
This parishioner
這個堂人異趣
he will tell everyone
他會跟大家講
This hall of wisdom
這個有智堂的堂
With you Zhitang's Tang
跟你智堂的堂
why is it different
為什麼不一樣
Then tell everyone what is called
然後告訴大家什麼叫做
Bangtang Shuangtang Guatang Genduotang
幫堂 雙堂 瓜堂 跟多堂
In this part, we often hear some
這部分我們常常聽到有一些跟堂
related health food and some
有關的健康食品還有一些
Some proteins related to sugar, etc.
和糖有關的一些蛋白質等等
It is very specialized in this research on the structure of sugar
它在糖的結構上有很專精的這個研究
and it also participates in the
並且它也參與了有關於
These analyzes of the structure of this glycoprotein
這個糖蛋白的結構的這些分析
and the analysis of the functions of these proteins in relation to sugars and sugars
還有糖和糖有關的這些蛋白質的功能的分析
Recently in our genome center
最近在我們基因體中心
We are under the leadership of the University's Dean Au
我們在大學的歐院長的領導下
We started to make sugar-based vaccines against cancer
我們開始以糖為主來做抗癌的疫苗
Everyone has said that vaccines are used to prevent infectious diseases
大家講過疫苗是用來預防傳染病的
But we can now use this sugar-based
但是我們現在可以用以糖為主的這個
to target such a vaccine to treat cancer
來標的這樣的疫苗來治療癌症
this is something new
這是很新的東西
So you don't need to come here today
所以今天大家來一定是不需此行
Can get a lot of scientific knowledge
可以得到很多的科學上的知識
But the upper layer, apart from being a good scientist
但是上層它除了是一個好的科學家以外
It's also usually a good scientist
它也是通常一好的科學家
After a very high level
很高的境界以後
Science and art can probably be combined
科學跟藝術是大概能夠合在一起的
So he ended up telling us
所以他最後我們跟大家講說
What kind of connection does Tanggen axion have?
堂根軸子有什麼樣的關聯性的
really delicate thing
真的是很微妙的事情
So we are very happy to have such a rich theme today
所以我們今天好高興有這麼豐富的題材
You can come and listen to the introduction given by the upper level
可以來聆聽上層給我們做這樣的一個介紹
We'll have 30 minutes of Q&A later
我們等一下還會有30分鐘的Q&A的時間
So guys we're going to let the red-specific researcher
所以各位我們就讓紅特定研究員
finish all first
先全部講完
That's a problem, we'll ask it later
那有問題我們在後面再來問
ok, here we are again thanking the upper echelons
好 那在這裡我們再次謝謝上層
to give this wonderful speech
來做這個很精采的演講
let us welcome him with a round of applause
讓我們以熱烈的掌聲來歡迎他
good
好
Thanks
謝謝
First of all, thanks to Vice President Chen
首先感謝陳副院長
my last introduction
我最後的介紹
Thank you for the experience here
感謝各位來賓歷練這邊
feel honored today
今天感到很榮幸
Can be invited by Vice President Chen
能夠陳副院長的邀請
Then I'm here to tell you about sugar
那我來這邊跟大家介紹一下有關於糖方面
to be honest
那說坦白話
Because what I asked before were all scientific articles
因為以前在問講的都是屬於科學性的文章
scientific stuff
科學的東西
Today I'm going to talk about popular science
今天要講的是科普
it took a lot of time
就花了不少時間
prepare again
再重新去準備
Otherwise I'm actually giving myself a challenge
不然我實際上是給自己一個挑戰
that is often
那常常就是在
on the sugar side
在有關於糖這一邊
is often asked
就是常常有人在問
It is the sugar next to the word and the sugar next to the word
就是到底這個有字旁的糖跟有字旁的糖
what's the difference
到底有什麼差別
what's going on
到底是什麼情況
Then the content of my speech today
那我今天的演講內容
roughly divided into seven parts
大概會分成七個部分
I mean, in the dipping medicine you got
我就是說各位拿到的那個沾藥裡面
The last paragraph has seven parts that are
最後一段有七個部分就是
I will introduce you to this place
我就會按照這一個地方來跟大家做介紹
at the beginning
那一開始
First, let me introduce to you that there are sugar and heels next to the words.
先來跟大家介紹就是有字旁的糖跟
A general introduction to sugar next to the five characters
五字旁的糖的一般性的介紹
that first of all
那首先就是
There is a definition of sugar next to the word
有關於這個有字旁的糖的定義
Then you can know that
那各位可以知道就是
sugar is composed of carbon, hydrogen and oxygen
是糖是由碳氫氧所組成
its molecule is
它的分子是
That is Cm, H2O, N
就是Cm,H2O,N
N can be equal or unequal
N可以等分也可以不等
Then here you can see that
那這裡你可以看得到就是
In fact, the ratio of the number of hydrogens to oxygens
實際上它的氫跟氧的數目的比
exactly like your water
剛好跟你的水一樣
so we just call it carbohydrates
所以我們就稱它為碳水化合物
like this
就這樣子來的
It is this carbon and this water
就是這個碳跟這個水
that's on the english side
那在英文這邊
In English, we call it Cup Hydrate
英文這邊我們稱為Cup Hydrate
Then this Cup Hydrate
那這個Cup Hydrate
You have to take a closer look
各位要仔細看一下就是
Because carbon in English is Cup N
因為碳的英文就是Cup N
The water is Hydrate
那水呢就是Hydrate
But the combination of these two words
但這兩個字合起來
Remove an N in the middle
中間要去掉一個N
So everyone, please write the English word Cup Hydrate
所以各位請問寫這個Cup Hydrate這個英文字
You don't write Cup N Hydrate
你不要寫Cup N Hydrate
One more N is wrong
多了一個N那就錯了
This is the possible name of Cod N
這個是Cod N可能名稱
Then there is another alias
那另外還有一個別名
This is the one that can also be called Sugar
就是這個也可以稱它是Sugar
This is the name of the wise life
這就是英明生命的稱呼
sugar classification
糖的分類
Basically they all have sugar can see
大致上他們都有糖糖可以看到
one is monosaccharide
一個就是單糖
that's a candy
那就是一個糖
are some of our common
就是我們常見的一些
From Five Tangs or Six Tangs
從五湯糖或者六湯糖
are some simple sugars
是一些單糖
A disaccharide is two monosaccharides joined together
雙糖就是兩個單糖合在一起
three to nine sugar
三到九個糖
we call it fructose
我們就稱它為果糖
This is a translation of the Chinese translation
這是中文翻譯的一個翻譯
if polysaccharide
如果是多糖的話
more than ten polysaccharides
多糖就會十個以上
we call it polysaccharide
我們就稱它為多糖
In addition there is
另外還有就是
real sugar
現形的糖
Let's practice layers of sugar
我們一層串的糖練起來
then a line like
然後像一條線一樣
this form of sugar
這種現形的糖
Most require two or more
大部分都要兩個或三個以上
Another one is
另外還有一種就是
Apart from this appearance
除了這個現形外
It also has this policy
它還有這個策略
So this is more than a general biomolecule
所以這個就比一般的生物分子
more complicated
來得複雜一點
We all know that the river is dry and sour
我們都知道說像河乾酸
one hair straight face
一條毛一直臉
If it is a half-white paper, it is also an ecological face.
如果是半白紙的話也是生態一條這樣臉
But the sugar is different, the sugar is the same
但糖不一樣,糖就是一條一樣
it can, the side can be long
它可以,旁邊還可以長
And sometimes it's not long and not just one
而且有時候不長還不只是一條
can be long
可以長很多條
This is a bit more complicated
這個就是比較複雜一點
The difference with this sugar is here
有這款的糖的差別是在這裡
Generally speaking, if there is sugar in this category, we place
有這款的糖一般來說我們放置
All carbon chiral compounds
所有的碳手化合物
If we put on the carbon hand compound
如果我們放在碳手化合物上
Let's talk about this sugar
我們就講有這款的糖
probably can't be wrong
大概就不會有錯
So this time carbs are using it to succeed
所以這次碳合物都是用它來成功
So include things like steel sugar, starch, cellulose
所以包括像鋼糖、澱粉、纖維素
Or soaked polysaccharide extraction, etc.
或者是淋漬多糖提等
These are sugars with this
這些都是用有這款的糖
The sugar dipped in sugar refers to some sweet sugar
那淋漬糖的糖就是指一些有甜味的糖
such as glucose, fructose, maltose
像葡萄糖、果糖、麥芽糖這些
Let's just call it dipped sugar
我們就稱它是淋漬糖的糖
that's because making sugar
那所以因為做糖
We will all pour some sugar is 300 lots
我們全部會淋一些糖是300手
does this have something to do with it
跟這個有關係嗎
then you go directly to see
那你直接去看
We usually cannot find the word sugar in water
我們都通常在水裡面去找不到糖這個字
really can't find
真的找不到
to see later
後來去看
just found out
才發現說
The word sugar was invented by Shiguo in the Five Dynasties
糖這個字是五代食果才發明的
So in the early years of the book
所以在本上初年
The annotation in the management is called fish wild
管理裡面的註解叫做魚野
so this makes sense
所以這個是有道理的
So if you are in the sugar is in the sea water
所以你如果在糖是上海水裡面
If you see the word sugar
有看到這個糖這個字的話
that's strange
那才怪
just very
就是很
It is the invention of the word
就是這個字的那個發明
When you talk about sugar, you will think of this sugar
那講到糖就會想到這糖
So this candy is in Taiwan
那這糖在台灣來說
It is a very important industry in the early days
是早期是非常重要的一個產業
So this used to be our Taiwan government
所以這曾經是我們台灣政府
a big layoff
很大的一個裁員
then here you will see
那在這裡會有看到
Here is a photo I found from two steps
這是我從兩步上找到的一個照片
very old
非常古老
So the face-to-face words at that time
所以那個時候的面的話
from the right side
從右邊面過來的
that this is the first
那這個是第一個
it's factory
這很工廠
it's about this
就是關於這個
Use this dry test to help raw materials
用這個乾測來幫助原料
So think of this sugar factory
所以想到這個糖廠
This part reminds me of my old hometown
這個部分就會讓我想起我以前的故鄉
I live in Qigu Township, Tainan County
我住在台南縣氣谷鄉
The part of Naqigu Township near the sea is Sunyan
那氣谷鄉靠海的部分是曬岩
but come in a little more
但是呢再進來一點
Just go home and get to the West Dome side
就是往家裡鎮拿到西穹這一邊
It's all kind of dry
都是種乾燥
it was like this at that time
在那個時候都是這樣
so then will
所以那時候會
From small to large
從小到大
grew up in this field
在這個沿田長大
Because the mother is the employee
因為是母親是員工
So what I miss most at that time
所以那個時候我最懷念的
If you say that everyone has gone to Yanqi Valley and Yanshan
這個如果說各位有去沿氣谷沿山
The one that I miss the most is
一個是我最懷念的就是
his evening
他的黃昏
That sunset is really beautiful
那個夕陽夕下真的很漂亮
At night, you can really see the sky full of stars.
晚上的話是真的可以看到滿天星的
because you can see it's flat
因為各位可以看到這是平的
As far as the eye can see
一望無盡
It is more difficult in Taipei now
現在在台北市這個就比較難
The other one is New Years
那另外一個就是新年
This Taipei Qigu Township
這個台北氣谷鄉
like a lot of private breasts
像私密乳乳很多
That private breast is actually the best private breast
那私密乳其實私密乳最好吃
It's about 8-12 taels
是大概8-12兩
you don't buy that
你不要去買那個
Don't buy the one that weighs more than one catty
你不要去買那個一斤以上的
Anything over a catty is too old.
一斤以上的那已經都太老了
but now it's different
但現在不一樣
Now they are selling big
現在賣的都是好大
when we raised
我們以前養的時候
This is about 8-12 taels, the most tender and delicious
這個大概是8-12兩是最嫩最好吃
Otherwise, you can still enjoy
不然各位還可以去欣賞
that black skin milk
那個黑面皮乳
This is a special product of the seven-inch incense
這個是七吋香這一根的一個特產
So I thought Qigu came from Yantian
所以想到七穀從鹽田過來
That is to plant these fields
那就是都種這些這田
Then this former classmate has
那這個以前同學就有的就在
Parents need to show up at this job
父母就要堂場這間工作
So everyone knew
所以小時候大家都知道
many little trains
很多的小火車
Then pull the cane
然後就拉著甘蔗
Then I went to steal sugarcane and eat it
然後就去偷拉甘蔗下來吃
So many people have this experience
所以很多人都有這種經驗
Then you see here, that is to say
那在這裡各位看到就是說
Zhuzhi Pond in Taiwan
在台灣的竹枝池
It describes the Zhetian
它就描述了這個浙田
So you can see Zhetian Luanqin B77
所以可以看到浙田亂琴B77
I think you'll see it's all turquoise
我覺得說你會看到這個都是碧綠色的
big and wide
很大很寬廣
Several kilometers, tens of thousands of hectares
好幾公里好幾萬公頃
Zhetian
都是種過浙田
People along the way call it Green Mud Mud
一路人稱為綠泥泥泥
This is because everyone, after growing up
這個就是因為各位這個長了以後
There's everything in this dry field
這個乾浙田裡面什麼都有
what has the most snakes
什麼最多蛇最多
Mouse, all of these are in it
老鼠各個這一些都在裡面
And this one is because it looks east and west
然後這個因為長得它東保西山
If it gets mixed in, it will be like Ming Geng
如果攪進去就跟明耕一樣
just be careful
就要很小心
So every time you harvest
所以每次在採收的時候
I also saw that many creatures ran out of the machine in the past
又看到機器過去有很多生物就跑出來
Then this bundler B7 talks about Brin
那這個捆仔B7談布林
Only save this page to think about the stars
只留著這一頁想群星
That of course took the dry parts
那個當然就是拿了這些乾澀的部分
This page is probably for these women
這頁大概就是給這些女人
So these are trendy things
所以這些是思潮性的東西
Of course now
當然現在的話
Your guides have been talking about
各位的指導現在一直在講
life and death woman
就生死女人
So actually let these Zhetian
所以其實讓這些浙田
These confinement oils may now be converted to storage
這些月子現在的機油可能可以轉變成以存
This is some recent development
這個是最近的一些發展
Then of course this candy because we
那當然這個糖因為我們
have been inseparable from the relationship
一直脫離不了關係
Because Taiwan has been selling sugar
因為台灣一直是在賣糖
So a lot of sugar is added to a lot of these foods
所以很多糖都是加在很多的這些食品裡面
So you can see something like
所以各位可以看到像
candy biscuit pastry or soda
糖果 餅乾 糕點或者是汽水
these are
這些是
Can't get rid of sugar
都脫離不了糖
about two months ago
在大概兩個多月前
It was reported in the newspaper
那個報紙上面就報
United States This is the latest study in the United States
美國這是美國最新的研究
It states that there are approximately 180,000 people worldwide
它指出全世界大概有18萬個人
because
因為
love this sugary drink
喜歡喝這個糖的飲料
and lose their lives
而丟掉性命
That's mainly because
那這個主要都是因為
Get Diabetes Secondary Sex
得到糖藥病第二性
then this question is
那這個問題就
quite serious
蠻嚴重的
that this
那這個
me about this drink
我關於這個飲料
like the soda part
像汽水的部分
you can see
各位可以看到
hard to imagine
很難以想像
I will give you an example
我會舉個例子給大家聽
For chemistry this is very good at doing all kinds of different
對化學這樣很會做各種不同的
like this orange soda
像這個橘子汽水
Have you all been back?
各位都有回過嗎
Fanta
芬達
I saw it on a certain website, that is to say
某一網就看到就是說
That factory is making Fanta orange soda
那個工廠在製造芬達橘子汽水
I haven't seen it come again
怎麼都沒有看到它再橘子來
Then it can
然後它就可以
Cases of orange soda are sold
一箱一箱的橘子汽水就賣出去
this is wesp
這個是wesp
If you are interested, you can also see
各位如果有興趣也可以看
You just go to the petal material store
你只要去花瓣材料店
then you buy some coloring
然後你買一些色素
buy some fragrance
買一些香精
and then some sugar
然後另外就是一些糖
We also pay attention to color, fragrance and sweetness when doing research
我們做研究也講究色香味氣甜
You almost made this chem soda good
你差不多把這個化學汽水做得好
I also brought fragrance here for comparison.
我這邊還對比帶了香精來
everybody
各位
if interested
如果有興趣
you can smell it
你可以來聞一下
I have bubble tea essence here
我這邊有泡沫紅茶香精
Absolutely the same as the black tea you drink
絕對跟你喝的紅茶絕對是一樣的
You can't run away if you drink it
你喝起來絕對跑不掉
The second is the flavor of the meat
第二個就是肉的香精
what is the flavor of your meat
你肉的香精是什麼
It's the instant noodles you eat
就是各位吃的泡麵
Instant noodles are not beef noodles
泡麵裡面不是什麼牛肉麵
What instant noodles, those meaty ones
什麼什麼泡麵那些肉的
everything is your taste
全部就是你的味道
Then there are strawberries, don't you know?
那還有草莓你們沒有知道吧
strawberry is your parent a lot of strawberry flavor
草莓就是你的家長很多草莓味嗎
There's also strawberry flavor here
這邊也有草莓香精
depends on what flavor you want
就看你要什麼香精
we chemists can
我們化學家就可以
then give me some
那你給我一點
what are you happy about
那都高興什麼
Glad that many things belong to chemistry
高興很多東西都是屬於化學
It's actually not good for your body
其實弄得對身體並不好
So here is to remind everyone
所以在這邊是要提醒大家
because these should drink less
因為這些要少喝
Because I'm afraid of polluting the site
因為我怕把場地給污染
because of this essence
因為這個香精
Once I open it up
我一打開一分下去的話
Maybe you'll smell it later
可能你們等一下就聞到
great taste
很大口的味道
if you are interested
就假如你們有興趣
interested in
有興趣
include end wanted
包括結束想要的
If you look at it
你們一看的話
welcome to the front
歡迎到前面這邊來
So when it comes to this candy, we will often encounter it.
所以講到這個糖我們就會常常碰到就是
Yi'er's businessman Tang, he would rather buy that candy
義兒的商人湯,他寧買那個折糖他都行對
Then he will want to find some sugar substitutes, so
那他就會想要找一些代糖,是這樣
The most commonly used sugar substitute is this saccharin
那代糖最常用的就是像這個糖精
So far, the problem with saccharin is that some people still say it’s OK.
那這個糖精的問題到目前就是一直還是有人說OK
Some people say that it will come by itself, but there is still no one who is sure about this thing
有人說會自來,那現在這個東西一直還是沒有一個很確定
The other one that everyone often encounters is Aspatine
另外一個就是大家常常會碰到的就是Aspatine
Aspatine is a bipectide, which is a biecological sugar
Aspatine是一個Bipectide,就是一個雙生態的一個糖
It's actually an Aspatidase
實際上它是一個Aspatidase
This is Fanning Ammon
這邊是Fanning Ammon
So it's a two amino acid glued together
所以它是一個兩個胺基酸黏起來的
But the point is here, the point is this
但重點就是在這裡,重點是這個
There's a methyl here, so it's a fat rib
這邊有一個甲基,所以它是一個脂肋
It is a fatty rib, the methyl, the fatty rib
它是一個脂肋,那這個甲基這個脂肋
So after our body decomposes
所以在我們身體分解了以後
i want to hear something
我想聽什麼東西
false lips
就是假唇
Because this hydrolysis is to get false lips
因為這個水解就是得到假唇
Then this false lip will be very bad for our body
那這個假唇會對我們的身體很不好
for example eyes
譬如說眼睛
Many people who drink fake alcohol suffer from insomnia
很多喝假酒的就眼睛失眠
So this is not good for long-term use
所以這個呢長期使用並不好
So if you get a chance to go out and buy coffee
所以各位如果有機會出去買咖啡
If you see a text next to it called
如果說你看到旁邊有寫一個叫做
school girl call
學女生叫一口
still
還是
forgotten
忘記了
I forgot
我忘記了
this one
就是這一種
Aspacatin
Aspacatin
you must not add
你千萬不要加
because the coffee is hot when you add it
因為你一加咖啡是熱的
break down faster
分解得更快
False lips will come out
就有假唇就會出來了
so what
那所以呢
usually someone is talking
通常有人在講
What to say about sugar substitutes
要講什麼用代糖
Here
在這邊
I am
我是
there is a personal suggestion
就有個人的建議
Does not represent any of my positions
不代表我任何的每個人的立場
My personal because I got it from Wikipedia
我個人的因為我從危機百科
to find
去找
I now have a description of him
我現在有關於他的描述
everyone to fancy
各位到花式
You can easily buy field bureaus
你很容易可以買得到田局
but very strange
但是很奇怪的
Tianjutang in Taiwan
在台灣田局堂
has not been very hot
一直不是很熱絡
also can not buy
也買不到
But what I know about this thing is
但這個東西我所了解的是
I've been through a lot of business interests
我經過到很多的商業的利益
In the U.S
在美國
It has never let this Tianjutang
它就一直不讓這個田局堂
Why did you enter the U.S. market?
進到美國市場為什麼
Because those who sold the hall have already
因為賣堂的那些已經
the market occupied
佔據的那個市場
it doesn't want to let it out
它不想放出去
Taiwan is following the United States
台灣都跟著美國走
this is a big problem
這是一個很大的一個問題
so in japan
所以在日本
in south america
在南美洲
in the mainland
在大陸
In fact, many of them use Tianjutang
其實很多都是用田局堂
So if you have elders
所以如果說各位有長輩
Then there is the problem of diabetes
然後有糖尿病的問題
then you really crave sugar
然後你真的很想吃糖
My suggestion is that you can buy a field bureau
我建議是你可以去買田局
haven't eaten
沒有吃過
that leaf
那個葉子
you take it off and wash it
你摘下來洗乾淨
mouth is very sweet
含嘴巴就很甜
So the one you really want to eat
所以真的想吃的那個
can watch
可以看
I just provide it as a reference for you
我只是提供給大家當個參考
So the above is the first bulk I think
所以以上是我想的第一大部分
The second part is to introduce to you
第二的部分要來跟大家介紹就是
These single or double halls we often see in our life
我們這堂生活常常看到的這些單堂或雙堂
Or some introductions of widowed or multiple halls
或是寡堂或是多堂的一些介紹
We often share the same points in this life
這個大家這堂生活裡面常常會同分
before that
那要講之前
I still want to give you
我還是要先給大家
That's the simplest thing about this
就是有關於這個最簡單的這些
Church structure
堂的結構
have different levels
有各個不同的層面
some high school, some college
有的是高中、有大學的
even the elderly
甚至是長者
This is a more professional structure
這個是比較專業的結構
generally speaking
這裡一般來說
Take Pratang's History
以普拉堂的歷史
There are roughly three ways of expressing
大概有三種表示方法
The first one is feature projection
第一個就是feature projection
This feature is the professor
這個feature就是這位教授
190 Nobel Prizes in Chemistry
190的諾貝爾化學獎
He is because of the recognition of the contribution between the halls
他就是因為表彰化在堂之間的貢獻
It's his habit to turn into this form
他的習慣是化成這樣子的形態
The other professor is an English professor named Harris
另外一個教授是英文的教授叫Harris
Harris Projection
Harris Projection
He is also a major in German
他也是德文學學長
He likes to turn him into such a form
他喜歡把他談化成這樣的一個形態
we do chemistry
我們做談化學的
We like to turn the conversation into something like this
我們喜歡把談化成這樣的形態
Because of this configuration we know
因為這個構型我們才會知道
What kind of position is its replacement actually in?
它的取代其實是在什麼樣的位置
We will understand its planning
我們才會去了解它的劃性
Talk about the half-blank paper we just talked about
談跟我們剛剛講的半白紙
Or where is the difference in Ha Giang Sour?
或者是河江酸不一樣的地方是在哪裡
is at this link at this place
是在這個鏈結的這個地方
Ha Jiang acid uses zero acid radicals to link each sugar
河江酸是用零酸根來鏈結每一個糖
so it doesn't get any stereochemistry
所以它沒有清得到任何立體化學
If it is half white paper it is an ecological piece
如果是半白紙它是形成生態件
It's AMR half-pink minmin
它是AMR半粉旻旻
It also doesn't have any stereochemistry
它也沒有任何立體化學
but sugar is different
但是糖不一樣
If you connect this candy with another candy
你這個糖跟另外一個糖連的話
This place can be down or up
這個地方就有朝下或是朝上
You link one sugar and you get two Ken's excesses
你鏈結一個糖就有兩個肯的溢多物
This is where it gets complicated
這個是它複雜的地方
What about the second one?
第二個呢
There are several OH positions in one sugar
糖一個糖這邊有好幾個OH的位置
These positions can have the opportunity to connect with it
這些位置都可以有機會來跟它連
Then the sugar with the side chain we just talked about will come like this
那就有我們剛剛講的側鏈的糖就這樣子來
Because it's not only half points it can have other
因為它不是只有半分它可以還有其他的
It can even sugar
它這些都可以連糖
In that case, the complexity of sugar will be more
那就這樣的話就糖的這個複雜度就比較多
So you have to remember that
所以各位要記得就是
Downward we call AVA
朝下的我們稱為AVA
upward we call beda
朝上的我們稱為貝達
This is up and down
這個是上跟下
This is such a distinction
這個是有這樣的一個區分
What about the common lancandy?
那各位常見的瀾碳糖
One is the opposite side of nucleotide
一個就是核肝酸反面
It's like RNA we call ribose
就是像RNA我們稱為核糖
Then if the oxygen is missing at No. 2
那如果2號的地方這個氧不見的
This we call deoxyribose
這個我們叫做去氧核糖
the building blocks of DNA
就是DNA的組成單元
Then there is another Wuhan sugar, the most common one is ribose
那還有一個武漢糖最常見的就是核糖
Because of this wood, if you take this
因為這個木團你如果把這個
This place of Yuhao is restored
魚號這個地方給還原
reduced sugar
就變成還原的糖
This we call xylitol
這個我們稱為木糖醇
Xylitol
木糖醇
then this is
那這個就是
You often see it in advertisements, right?
各位常常廣告上就看到對不對
you saw that ad
你們看到那個廣告
you are surprised
你覺得很訝異
He took the lead in that ad
那個廣告他就牽了一頭
a naked head
一頭那個裸頭
Do you have
有沒有
feel very strange
都覺得很奇怪
What does this naked head have to do with this?
怎麼這個裸頭跟這個有什麼關聯
Later, just by looking at it, I knew that
後來只是一看就知道說
this naked head
這個曬裸頭
Bare head
曬裸頭
so he
所以他就
The ad took the lead
廣告就牽了一頭
come with the bare head
一頭那個裸頭來
So everyone feels very
所以大家覺得很
think this ad
覺得這個廣告
three very
三很有
creativity
創意
that in addition
那另外
common xylose
常見的這個木團糖
The most common is
最常見的就是
like glucose
像剛才的葡萄糖
with glucose
跟葡萄糖
Everyone
那各位
Glucose and Glucose
葡萄糖跟葡萄糖
now in our body
現在在我們的身體裡面
are interchangeable
是可以互換的
That swapped this
那互換的這個
So now there is a passing
所以現在有經過的
after a pro-acidification
一個臨酸化以後
it's just the simple fact
那這邊只是簡單的事實
Let everyone understand the relationship between these two sugars
讓大家了解一下這兩個糖為什麼會復換的關係
Then the location of this place in the future
那這個以後這個地方的位置
It can be opened into a full
它可以打開變成一個全
So we say that glucose is a whole sugar
所以我們講葡萄糖就是屬於全糖
just whole sugar
就全 全糖
Then this place can balance
那這個地方它可以平衡
Can become a form with two swords and a pure
可以變成一個有雙劍又帶有一個純的這種形態
and then overflow
然後之後再溢夠化
So it will become this CO double sword running to the second carbon
所以會變成這個CO雙劍跑到第二個碳上
At this time, it is called turning into copper sugar
那這個時候就叫做變成銅糖
Then when the back is relaxed, it becomes this
然後這個仰在緩起來以後就變成這個
That's fructose
那這個就是果糖
So it can be replaced in this place
所以它這個地方可以復換
So often we might help learn
所以我們常常可能會幫學到
Speaking of So-Called Whole or Fructose
講到所謂的全糖或果糖
It's the difference here
就是在於這邊的區分
fructose
那各位果糖
Fructose, you can hear fructose clearly, right?
各位果糖聽到分明果糖對不對
Then you should pay attention
那各位要注意
Because this sugar is not only its content
因為這個糖不僅它的含量
The second thing to look at is its glycemic index
第二個要看的就是它的生糖指數
It means how quickly it gets into your blood after you eat it
就是說你吃了以後它多快就跑到你的血液裡面
Resist your sugar concentration
抵抗你的這個糖的濃度
sugar smaller and faster
糖越小越快
So eating jaggery is the fastest
所以吃斑糖最快
Then we eat instant noodles and rice
那我們吃便粉吃米飯
Everyone just had dinner, right?
剛剛各位剛剛吃的晚餐對不對
rice it belongs to this kind of pra sugar that is aggregated
米飯它是屬於聚合的這種普拉糖
It still needs to be hydrolyzed and made again
它還要經過水解還要再做了
So it will be slower if you want that.
所以那個要那個就比較慢了
So if you say you eat fructose
所以各位如果說你吃果糖
we want to separate fructose
我們想要分離果糖
If it's real fructose spots like this
如果是真的像這樣的果糖斑斑的話
Then I can assure you that you will eat it
那可以跟各位保證你吃下去
It's about to float and go into the blood vessel.
馬上飄了就要到血管裡面去了
Therefore, those with a high glycemic index should try to lose weight as much as possible
所以生糖指數高的要盡量少胖
The other common six-carbon sugar
那另外常見的六碳糖
Except for praline
除了普拉糖以外
This is Pratam
這個是普拉糖
The other is glucosamine
另外一個就是葡萄胺糖
Napra sugar structure
那普拉糖的結構
Comparing everyone with Pratam
各位跟普拉糖的比起來
There will be a difference in the position of No. 2
會有二號這個位置的不同
It would have been OH light source fine
它本來是OH的光源精細
Now become an NH2
現在變成一個NH2
This is called Putang Antang
這個叫浦堂安堂
The other is glucose
另外一個就是葡萄酸糖
It is the place where No. 6 is oxidized
就是6號這個地方氧化
become an acid
變成一個酸
Another one is mannose
另外還有一個就是甘露糖
Mannose is the position of No. 2
甘露糖就是2號的這個位置
it flips
它翻轉
originally under
本來是在下
Flip now to top
現在翻轉變成到上
galactose
另外是半乳糖
this is
這個就是
For example, the comparison is the position of No. 4
比方的比較就是4號的位置
This place was originally under
這個地方本來在下
Flip now to yes up
現在翻轉變成是上
Galactose is the place where 6 minutes of NH2
半乳糖就是這個地方6分鐘的NH2
In addition, this is salt bath sugar
另外這個就是鹽澡糖
We call it LFVCOS
我們稱為LFVCOS
Another one is Vamos
還有一個就是Vamos
Vamos We do not have
Vamos我們人體裡面並沒有
It is inside the plant
它是植物裡面成有
So the sugar candies that I show here
所以各位我這邊所秀的這幾個甘糖
It's all inside the cells of our body
都是我們的身體細胞裡面
These sugars that appeared
出現的這幾個糖
So that is to say
所以也就是說
if you want to pass the season
如果想要季節過
not many seasons
不用季很多
The amount of sugar does not need to be a lot
糖量都不用季很多
Just these few are enough
就這幾個就夠了
Probably more than 90% reliable
大概就可以靠得90%以上
Another candy that I must introduce to you is stinky liquid acid
另外一個糖必須要跟大家介紹的就是臭液酸
This is a nine carbon sugar
這個是一個九個碳的糖
The earliest discovery of this smelly acid was from bird's nest
這個臭液酸最早的發現是從燕窩
this is bird's nest
這是燕窩
Everyone knows the formation of bird's nest, right?
燕窩那大家都知道燕窩的形成吧
The formation of bird's nest is to use the smelly liquid of swallows
燕窩的形成是利用燕子的臭液
and then to form
然後之後去形成的
That's because it's the stinky liquid of swallows
那所以因為是燕子的臭液
So we specifically translated this stinky liquid acid
所以我們專門就翻譯這個臭液酸
that's how it came
是這樣來的
It was very expensive to buy this smelly liquid acid in the early days
那早期要買這個臭液酸非常貴
too expensive to lose to gold
貴到不會輸給黃金
that is really expensive
那個真的很貴
That later is now because you can get from that egg
那後來現在是因為可以從那個雞蛋
you can go and get this stinky acid
就可以去拿到這個臭液酸
So the price will drop a lot all of a sudden.
所以那個價格一下子偏就會降很多
So now this thing is cheap
那所以現在這個東西就變便宜了
Then everyone can buy
然後大家都可以買得到
Then I'll talk about this stinky acid in a moment
那等一下我會講到有關於這個臭液酸
It's a social special paradise about bird's nest
就是有關於燕窩的社會特別天堂
good
好
That
那
The above are monosaccharides
以上是單糖
Next, I would like to introduce you to the introduction of disaccharides.
那接下來跟大家介紹有關於雙糖方面的介紹
The most important thing about double sugar is this folding sugar
那雙糖最重要就是這個折糖
Nazhe candy is composed of glucose and fructose
那折糖就是由葡萄糖跟果糖
disaccharide
所連接起來的一個雙糖
Then you speak with justice
那各位以正義的說法
sugar is easier to sugar
糖就比較容易生糖
So if you say it’s easy to get sugar
所以各位如果說容易生糖的話
sugar
糖就
basically eat less
就基本上要少吃
In addition, maltose
另外就是麥芽糖
That maltose is glucose and glucose
那麥芽糖就是葡萄糖跟葡萄糖
Alpha is pointing down
Alpha就朝下
Then E4 link
然後E4鏈接
This disaccharide we call
這個雙糖我們稱為
maltose
麥芽糖
and lactose
還有就是乳糖
Everyone has milk
各位有曾合牛奶
Or the baby drinks this milk
或者是嬰兒喝這個牛乳
There are galactose and glucose in it
這裡面有的就是半乳糖跟葡萄糖
Then it is hit face up
然後它是以朝上的被打
E4 sugar stem chain to link
E4的糖乾鏈來鏈接
When we were young or many people may have this lactose hydrolase in the body
在我們小時候或者很多人可能身體裡面都有這個乳糖水解酶
So you can successfully hydrolyze this disaccharide
所以你可以順利的把這個雙糖可以水解
into galactose and pula sugar
變成半乳糖跟普拉糖
and then use
然後來使用
but with age
但是隨著年齡的增長
like me
像我就是
lactose water
乳糖水
It's been a long time since I drank
年來很早就沒有喝了
That pair of lactose hydrolase will disappear
那對乳糖水解酶就會消失
What will happen if there is a lack
那缺乏的話會怎麼樣
When this disaccharide goes directly into the water, you will get lactic acid
這個雙糖直接進去淡泄就會得到乳酸
So you find it convenient and convenient for me to teach a bunch of lactose
所以你就發現我教一堆乳糖就會方便很方便
why is my stomach growling
為什麼肚子就開始叫
Half an hour will start to ask for sports cars
半個小時會開始要跑車的時候
so what about this
那所以這個要怎麼辦
Then I showed that no one has this kind of heart
那我表現到這個沒有人有這種心項
This lactose hydrolase will disappear
這個乳糖水解酶就會消失
Does it have that kind of lactose in foreign countries?
那這個在國外它會是有沒有那種乳糖的
Probably not available in Taiwan
台灣大概不太能夠買得到
But I will tell you a way
但是我會告訴大家一個方法
This is the only way to die
這隻死地才會生
What's the meaning
什麼意思
You just drink it, drink it, drink it
你就是喝了拉 拉了再喝
Pull again and drink again
再拉 再喝
trade your body for its memory
把你的身體換起它的記憶
will guide the lactose hydrolysis membrane to come out again
就會引導使這個乳糖水解膜再出來
then you can drink again
那你就可以再喝
That's another way
那這個就是另外一個方法
Then I will introduce to you
那接下來要跟大家介紹
That's when there's a lot of sugar
就是這個糖入了比較多的時候
Then he put the glucose
那剛才這個葡萄糖他把它
to one four one four
以一四一四
All sugar dry bonds of 1414
全部都是一四一四的糖乾鍵
then make a ring
然後煉成一個環
This we call ringhujing
這個我們稱為環胡精
that kind of
那這一類的
This kind of tree you can count it this glucose
這一類你可以算它的這個葡萄糖的樹木
if it is six
如果它是六個
We call it Afa
我們就稱為阿發
if there are seven we call beda
如果是七個我們就稱為貝達
If it's eight we call it Ama
如果是八個我們就稱為阿瑪
So what is the effect of this kind of Huang Hu Jing?
那這一類的黃胡精有什麼功效
He's here to help deliver the drug
他來幫這個藥物傳遞
what does that mean i mean
這個意思呢 我就是說
These O-curved concepts are actually clear water
這些O曲的觀念其實都是清水性
it's all extra tide
它都是潮外
but in this ring
但在這個環內
It is combing water
它是屬於梳水性
so everyone
所以各位
this is a model
這是一個模型
This is the model of loess gold
這是黃土金的模型
you can see it's red
你可以看到就是紅色的
The red one is tide
紅色那個是潮
out of the tide
潮外
middle part
中間的部分
is comb water
是梳水性
so there are some
所以有一些
it seems that the drug
看來藥物
it is not easy to dissolve in water
它不容易溶水
it will use this loess gold
它就會用這個黃土金
to be used as storage
來當作存地的東西
That is to say it can be used
也就是說它可以用
The effect of combing water
梳水性的那種作用
then go take this drug
然後去帶這個藥物
So this is loess gold
所以這個是黃土金
most commonly used
最常用的
But every time I see this molecule
但我每次看到這個分子
I just thought of another one
我就想到另外一個
Field Circle
田田圈
Everyone should be at Mr.Bona
各位應該在Mr.Bona
should always know
應該常常會知道
But this situation is really like
不過這個情況真的很像
But when I saw this, I thought of another one
但是我看到這個我還想到另外一個
When I was doing Ph.D. and research at Berkeley
以前在伯克萊做博士和研究的時候
At that time, the Berkeley chemistry department had a very important tradition
那個時候伯克萊化學系有一個很重要的傳統
It's all right, come to the Seminar
就是沒事的Seminar來
They will definitely prepare two boxes of Bona at 12 o'clock
他們在12點的時候一定會準備兩盒Bona
and then there's coffee
然後還有咖啡
They invite the speaker to chat with the teachers and students in the department
他們就邀請speaker跟系上的老師學生就下去聊天
They finally eat very simple
他們終於就吃得很簡單
They're finally just a piece of bona with a cup of coffee
他們就終於就是一塊Bona一杯咖啡
Then after eating, chat and go in to listen to the Seminar
然後吃完了以後聊一聊就進去聽Seminar
So at that time it was said No Bona, No Seminar
所以那個時候就是說No Bona, No Seminar
So as long as you don't prepare Bona
所以只要沒有準備Bona
No one will go to your Seminar
你的Seminar就沒有人要去
No coffee, No can't see
No coffee, No can't see
So our tradition of doing chemistry sometimes coffee
所以我們做化學的傳統有時候會咖啡
The word KAMISHI is also very special
KAMISHI這個字也很特別
THURSDAY-TRI
KAMIS-TRI
THURSDAY-TRI THURSDAY
KAMISHI KAMIS-TRI
So we mean to experiment
所以我們意思就是要做實驗
to try to know
去嘗試才會知道
do you just make it
是不是你就做出來
Another example is that you
另外一個假如說你這個
If it is not circular
假如它不是成環狀
but in a linear
而是成一個線形
put it in this shape
把它有這種形態
This is what you often see is starch.
這個各位就常見到的就是澱粉
There are two types of starch
澱粉有分兩類
This is linear starch
這個就是線形澱粉
That is, all of them use Alpha1414
就是全部都是用Alpha1414
rattan cable link
這樣子的藤蔘纖索鏈結
Another one is
另外一個就是
Starch with side chains
還有側鏈的澱粉
That is to say, at the place of No. 6
也就是說在六號這個地方
it can be connected again
它可以再連出去
and then form another
然後再形成另外
So we can see that
所以我們可以看到就是說
this number six is ​​that
這個六號是那個
There will be some side chain sugars in it
它裡面會有一些側鏈的糖
This side chain sugar is usually very long
這個呢側鏈糖通常都很長
This is a characteristic of starch
這個是澱粉的一個特性
Then everyone probably
那各位大概
in the last two weeks
在最近的這一兩個禮拜
Because the public account has the most pages in Taiwan is this Dudian fan
因為公帳全台灣的版面最多的就是這個獨電粉
Ladies and gentlemen, there are currently 21 kinds of chemical powders merged by the Department of Health and Hygiene
各位目前惡生署合併的有21種化學電粉
Manufacturers will make smart
廠商會製作聰明
he just adds something
他就是會去添加一些東西
like maleic acid
像是順丁西二酸
or dry maleic acid
或者是順丁西二酸乾
add these things
添加這些東西
to increase flexibility
來增加彈性
Everyone, if you look carefully
各位如果仔細去看
The Department of Health and Health can say that what can be added is fumaric acid
惡生署裡面可以說可以添加的是反丁西二酸
Why?
為什麼?
Because this is in our metabolism
因為這個是在我們的代謝裡面
In the silver gate acid cycle
在銀門酸循環裡面
Naturally there will be something like this
自然就會有產生這個東西
So this is what we have in our body
所以這個是我們身體裡面有的
is safe
是安全的
You can add this thing to make it more elastic
你可以添加這個東西去增加它的彈性
But why are manufacturers different
但是廠商為什麼不一樣
I will choose this again
我再去選這個
The price is too smart
價錢 對太聰明了
The manufacturer is like this
廠商這邊這樣喔
He is looking for cheap
他就是要找便宜喔
So this is the cheapest
所以這個最便宜喔
this is the cheapest
這個最便宜
When this hits water
這個一碰到水喔
He will be hydrolyzed
他就會水解嘛
become this thing
就變成這個東西
Oh, he is actually the manufacturer.
喔他其實廠商就是這樣子喔
He just wants to choose cheap
他就是要選擇便宜喔
And he doesn't care about other people's lives
然後他也不管其他人的生命喔
so everyone here
所以各位在這裡
I always thought it was a class with a chemist student
我一直以為是跟化學師的學生上課
I always talk
我都是講
You study chemistry and science
你學化學 學科學
You must have a compassionate heart
一定要有一個慈悲的心喔
You must not go to those harming something
你千萬不要去那一些害什麼東西
go go go go make money
去 去 去 去 去賺錢
So folks, because in the lives of students
所以各位 因為在學生的生命中
you can get some
你可以拿到一些
something poisonous
一些有毒的東西啊
some bad
一些不好的
for example
譬如說
you will get swimming
你隨便會拿到游泳
Swimming, you see who is unhappy, you have to return him to the cage
游泳你看誰不高興你就要給他回籠
I used to meet students at Tsinghua University who said
以前在清華也碰到學生說
Finishing the water is another matter
完水那是另外的喔
Another one is about liking a girlfriend
還有一個是說喜歡一個女朋友
because girls
因為女孩子
want to say make her sick
想說讓她生病
Let her go to the hospital to take care of her
讓她會到醫院去照顧她
Just wanted to say in her drink
就想說在她的飲料裡面
put poison on her
給她放有毒的東西
She gave her dogs
她就給她放狗類的
Turns out her girl didn't drink
結果她的女的沒喝到
It was a guy in her lab who drank
是她的同時驗室的一個男的喝到
In the end, that man had to undergo kidney dialysis.
結果那個男的要真身洗腎
Then you say these are
然後你說這些就是
how to say that
怎麼講就是那種
we're all talking about this
我們都在講說這種
make a fuss like this
鬧得跟這種
IQ has nothing to do with this kind of IQ
跟智商跟這種IQ是無關聯
So sometimes you're smarter
所以有時候反而你越聰明
On the contrary, I will do some stupid things more and more
反而越會做一些傻事
so this is
所以這個是
people also think
人們還覺得
my personal opinion
我的個人觀點
I still think the font Qunde
我還覺得得字體群德
still the most important
還是最重要的
kids teach it well
小孩子把它教好
get it done
弄好
In good health
身體健康
Then he will always find
那將來他總會找到
A place suitable for his development
一塊適合他發展的地方
like a rope
就像一顆繩子
will always find a suitable land for his development
總會找到一個適合他發展的土地
That
那
the one we just talked about
我們剛剛講的那個
DC diacid these
DC二酸這一些
You can use HPLC
你可以用HPLC
some to check
一些去檢驗
Then there is also the inspection method of this starch.
那也有關於這個澱粉的檢驗方式
Usually, points are used to test
通常都會用點來去做檢驗
So what you guys are doing, let's say
所以各位在做的假如說
you have high school kids at home
你家裡有高中的小孩
Or maybe we're doing some high school kids
或者是我們在做一些高中生
you usually learn that
你通常就會學到就是說
Use dots to test starch
用點可以來測試澱粉
is there any
到底有沒有
That means you just add
那就是說你只要加點
Point in the water will become
點在水裡面會變成
Iz-h
I3-4
will then become
然後會變成
half heavy color
半的重色
but if it has come into existence
但是它如果有變成存在
you will become very deep
你會變成很深的這種
blue
藍色
blue purple color
藍紫色這種顏色
then this
那這個的話
everybody
各位
this sandalwood
這個檀
If you didn't pay back
假如你不是還起來的
is open
是打開的
it will have
它會有
sort of like a spiral
有點像螺旋狀
that this spiral
那這個螺旋狀
like that shows
就像那所顯示
that this
那這個
You can see that
各位可以看到就是
this dot molecule
這個點分子
I just mentioned
我剛剛有講到
spiral
螺旋狀
that
那個
that shot hit
那個彈的中
The slow part in the middle belongs to crisp water
中間緩的那個地方是屬於酥水性
So point molecules can run into it
所以點分子可以跑到那裡面
It doesn't exist as I3-4 when you run there
跑到那裡面它就不是以I3-4存在
It is based on I2
它是以I2
For point molecules
對於點分子
what color is the molecule itself
那點分子本身是什麼顏色
It's very masculine
就是很深的男子色
that color is laid out
那個顏色就鋪入出來
So you can use that to detect
所以說你可以用那樣子來去檢測
The presence of this starch
這個澱粉的存在
everyone at the night market
各位在夜市
Or you don't have a shop at home
或者是你家裡沒有開店
You always go to buy this pen
你常常都會去買這個尾鈔筆
How does the end note pen identify this end note
那個尾鈔筆是怎麼來辨別這個尾鈔
That's actually very simple
那這個其實很簡單
because normal paper
因為一般的紙張
We're all made of ginger paper
我們都是用薑紙做成
When the paper was just finished
那這個紙張剛做好的時候
Actually they are bumpy
其實它們是凹凸不平
And all these companies that make paper
那所有的這些製造紙張的公司
It's going to treat its surface with ginger
它要把它表面做薑化的處理
Then this paper will be very average
那這個紙張才會很平均
very nice, so you can use
很漂亮的,讓你可以用
Well, this is also a normal paper dismantling.
那這也是一般做紙拆的
paper, which is made of cotton and thin cloth as cotton
紙,它是用棉花和瘦布來當作棉花
So we usually use this book
所以我們一般的這個書本用的
Or the material you are holding is paper
或者是各位手上拿的材料是用紙
are pulped
都是有經過漿化處理
There is no Chaohua, so Chaohua touches the water
那超化沒有,所以超化碰到水
It's okay, it can be dried and used
沒事啊,可以曬乾的還可以用
When the paper touches water, don't say that it will be polluted if the saliva is sprayed on it.
紙張碰到水,不要說什麼口水噴到就污染了嘛
That's because of the slurry treatment on it
那就是因為上面有那個漿化處理
So what is the general super ratio for?
所以一般的有超比是要幹嘛
there is nothing in it
它裡面沒有什麼東西
It's just a little bit easier, it's as simple as that
就是含點的容易,就這麼簡單
So that is to say, today if you take your color printer
所以也就是說,今天如果說拿你家的彩色印表機
Then I went to be this two thousand yuan
然後去當了這個兩千塊的
You print it out, then take it and buy it again
你拿印出來,然後拿去又是要去買
Of course it can hold that pen
那當然,它能拿那個筆
how to get dark blue
怎麼變得很深的藍色
it says you take that
它就說你是拿那個
That piece of ordinary paper went in
那這張一般的紙去進的
So this is how they identify super
所以這個是它們辨別有超的方法
But I always feel that some people who specialize in printing counterfeit banknotes are still very powerful
但是我總覺得有一些專門在印假鈔的人還是很厲害
He always had the ability to get paper that wasn't this ordinary
他總是有能力去拿到不是這種一般的紙張
always take this special paper
總是會拿這種特別的紙
The most special thing is that most people can't buy it
最特別的是一般人是買不到
It is usually the country that goes with a specific
通常都是國家去跟特定的這種
printing paper
印紙紙場去買
Ladies and gentlemen, let's talk about the report
各位我們講一句看到報道
i think i seriously misremembered
我認為我認真的記錯了
I didn't see the report a while ago
前一陣子又不見到報道
North Korea is the best
北韓最厲害
North Korea prints a lot of dollar bills
北韓印了很多美鈔
Do you have
有沒有
His reports are North Korean diplomats
他的報道就是北韓的外交官
he has a very important responsibility
他有一個很重要的責任
He wanted the hundreds of thousands of fake dollar bills that were given to him in the country
他要把國內所賦予給他的幾十萬的假的美鈔
be responsible for turning it into real money
要負責把它變成真鈔
then shipped back
然後運回去
So his production is really beautiful
所以他那個製作就真的很精美
Almost all machines are useless
幾乎是機器都用不出來
This is really the report
這個是真的有這樣的報道
It's mentioned in the west
在西部裡面就有提到
Another thing related to this is glycogen
另外還有一個跟這個有關的就是肝糖
glycogen in our body
肝糖在我們的身體裡面
It is accumulated in the liver
是累積在肝這邊
Glycogen is the same as the starch just now
肝糖也是一樣跟剛剛的澱粉
In fact, starch with side chains is very similar to
其實有側鏈的澱粉很像
It's also all Alpha-14 or Alpha-16 links
它也都是Alpha-14或是Alpha-16鏈接
But this part of its side chain is relatively short
但是它的這個側鏈的這個地方比較短
Can the starch we just talked about be chained for a long time, right?
我們剛剛講的澱粉是不是可以鏈到很長對不對
Glycogen is shorter
肝糖比較短
That's what glycogen looks like
那這個肝糖是這樣子
so after we ate
所以我們吃了以後
Will eat after carbohydrates
碳水後會吃了以後
Excess is stored in the liver
多餘的會儲存在肝臟的地方
That excess will sometimes easily form this fatty liver
那過量就會有時候會容易形成這個脂肪肝
So guys, if you guys go for that ultrasound
所以各位如果你們去做那個超音波
The doctor said, why does your liver look brighter?
醫生說你的肝怎麼會比較看起來比較亮
then you have to be a little tight
那你就要有點緊迅
Because when the five internal organs look dark, right?
因為當得這種五臟看起來都是暗的嘛對不對
If it is brighter, it is a tendency to have a fatty liver
比較亮那就是有點脂肪肝的傾向
Then you would even say that your liver may be the first half of
那甚至你會說你的肝可能第一半的
come a little bigger
來得大一點點
So how do we avoid fatty liver or diabetes
所以我們要如何避防脂肪肝或者是糖尿病
I actually think we're pretty much experts
其實我覺得我們非常專家
Because of avoidance of serious treatment
因為避防重視療
So the home of preventive medicine
所以避防醫學的家
avoidance of attention
避防重視療
so notice what
所以注意到是什麼
sports
運動
snack sugar sports
小吃糖都運動
this is the most important
這個是最主要
but i went to the doctor
可是我去看醫生
I almost freaked out after I saw the doctor
我看醫生後我差點嚇到
we all get sick sometimes
我們都是有時間生病
no time to exercise
沒有時間運動
Hello students
各位同學好
Then the next sentence is to say
然後後面一句話講就是說
You don’t take care of your health now, you want to take care of a doctor
你現在不養生你為了要養醫生
so really want to
所以還是真的是要
everyone can spare more time
大家能夠多出時間
able to exercise more
能夠多運動
Then talk about this Tuantan
然後講到這個端坦
what we just said
我們剛剛講的是
You if you can use your body to move
你如果你是可以用身體運動
it is capable
它是可力的
it's not powerless
它不是不可力的
so you can move around
所以你可以運動來去
Take the hepatopancreas in your liver to eliminate
把你的肝臟裡面的肝腸來消除
But some people are just poor
但是有一些人就是很可憐
He can't use this way
他沒有辦法用這樣子的方式
what is this
這就是什麼?
so-called genetic disease
就是所謂的遺傳性疾病
Guys, he heard it a while ago
各位前一陣子他有聽到
hepatoenteropathy
就是所謂的肝腸除肌症
There are so-called back municipalities
有就稱為所謂的盤背市政
Speaking of this back-to-back municipal
講到這個盤背市政
Be sure to listen to the seniors of our former Holy Medical Institute
一定要聽一下我們前聖醫所的學長
It is our Academician Chen Yiren
就是我們陳一仁從院士
He just developed this
他就是特別去開發了這個
Millet Long
Millet長
This is a glucose hydrolase
這是一個葡萄糖的水解酶
Then he can come and hydrolyze this
然後他可以來水解這個
accumulate this liver
累積這個肝臟
can come and save these little kids
可以來救這些小孩子
So because of this success story
所以因為這個成功的故事
Hawaii also made it into a movie
Hawaii還把它拍成電影
Also recruited two famous stars
還找來了兩個很有名的明星
Harrison Ford splits school with this Brandon
哈里遜福特跟這個布蘭頓分學
right
對不對
everybody
各位
when we saw this picture
我們看到這張照片的時候
I looked at the back one very carefully.
我特別仔細的去看後面的這個
back
盤背
The structure of the above plate is really good or bad
上面這個盤的結構還真的好壞
This is an M.I possible
這是一個M.I可能
Then he made several
然後他做了好幾部
that's all right
那個全部都是對的
so he really is
所以他真的是
i need someone special to go
我要找人特別去
to draw over there
去畫在那邊
Actually I think
其實我覺得說
That's Penguin
那是彭蛋白
That's glucose hydrolase
那這個是葡萄糖的水解酶
what is he holding
他到底牽著
very conceptual
很有些觀念
that this
那這個
I think they are great actors
我覺得他們演員很厲害
seems to drive well
好像駕駛十足
just very special
就是很特別
the other one is
那另外一個就是
polysaccharide kidney
年多糖腎
You see some
各位看到有一些
a pure disease
也就是一純性疾病
That is to say, the hydrolytic enzyme that your body lacks
就是說你身體缺乏的水解酶
which then leads to the accumulation of these sugars
然後導致於這些糖的累積
So this is some kind of acidic polysaccharide
那這個就是一些那種酸性的年多糖
Then it will cause the accumulation of this cell
然後就會造成它這個細胞的累積
Then this accumulates in the head
那這個累積在頭
Like this accumulates in the eyes, right?
像這個累積在眼睛對不對
eyes will swell
眼睛就會腫起來
accumulated in the head
累積在頭
swollen
腫起來
Then get fat in the heart
然後在心上就肥大
So these years polysaccharide
所以這些年多糖
It's really hard for the baby in the court, very poor
過堂寶寶真的很辛苦 很可憐
I think you should have
我想各位應該之前
have you seen these reports
你們有看到這些報導
That's a genetic disease
那這個都是屬於遺傳性的疾病
It's not the kid's fault
這不是小孩子的過錯
This is a parental home review
這是父母親家檢討
why do you say that
為什麼要這樣講
Because all of this is because
因為這一些都是因為
you need a pre-marital health check
你要做婚前健康檢查
This is very important
這個很重要
You must first understand what is inside your body
你要先了解你到底身體裡面
Do you have a recessive gene like that?
有沒有帶有那樣的隱性基因
if your dad has
如果說你爸爸有
Your mother will try to find
你媽媽就要盡量找沒有
If your father and mother have
假如你爸爸跟媽媽都有
you have a one in four chance
你就是有四分之一的機會
just as if
就是會彷彿
But here in Taiwan
但是台灣這邊就是
It just so happens that there is such a history
剛好就是有這樣的歷史
and he gave birth to a
而且他生了一個
He wants to bet a second time
他還想再賭第二次
He gave birth to three
就他生了三個都是
what do you say
那你說要怎麼辦
sometimes to god like this
有時候到老天爺這樣子
so this is very important
所以這個就是很重要
You must have a pre-marital health checkup before you get married.
就是結婚前一定要做婚前健康檢查
put some of these
把這一些的這些
you have to pay special attention to things
東西你就要特別注意
In Australia, the B-valve of Minlutan VII is particularly high
在澳洲,民流坦第七型的B-valve 特別高
This is for your reference
這個是給大家當個參考
Next, I will introduce to you the little tree
接下來跟大家介紹的是鮮為樹
Few trees, walk outside, plants are abundant in every way
鮮為樹,走在外面,植物各方面都有很多
fresh tree, if the leaves are picked off
鮮為樹,如果把葉子摘下來
Enlarge the leaves, and enlarge this place again
把葉子放大,再把這個地方再放大
Zoom in on the chair again and you'll see glucose here
再把椅子放大,你就看到這裡葡萄糖
It's all glucose
這個全都是葡萄糖
so link up
所以,連結起來
this one, its
這一個呢,它的
Here's the link, it's all using Bella 1,4
這邊的鏈結,它全部都是用貝拉1,4
It is different from the starch dry tank just now
跟剛剛的澱粉乾坦不一樣
The starch dry tank just now uses α1,4
剛剛的澱粉乾坦都是用α1,4
Bella
這邊是用貝拉
Bella 1,4, you will see its structure
貝拉1,4,你會看到它的結構
It has intramolecular clarity and intermolecular clarity
它有分子內的清見,分子間的清見
even have a face-to-face meeting
甚至有面跟面的清見
So the one on this side looks relatively flat
所以它這邊一所看起來是比較平面型
different
就不一樣
Could it be the person just now talking about what a computer is?
會不會是剛剛的人講電腦是什麼
You will choose right? The first number is not, the first number is flat
你會選的對不對?先為數不是,先為數是屬於平的
Then why do people eat powder to provide energy? Eating grass does not work
那為什麼人吃變粉提供能量?吃草卻不行
Then this is very simple, because we only have Ah Fa, the bathroom does not need to charge money
那這個就很簡單,因為我們人只有阿發浴室不要很收錢
We don't have a backup, we don't have a backup bathroom don't charge very much
我們沒有備打,我們沒有備打浴室不要很收錢
So people are happy for food, not food
所以人都是高興為的食物,不是食品
Of course it will help you defecate and lose weight, it won't be cheap
那當然有利你排便可以減肥,不會便宜
Those grassy ones, why do most of them eat grass and turn them into powder?
那草卻性的,大部分為什麼吃草,吃變粉都可以
The exception is often, let's say ordinary grass, as its stomach is more
這個例外常常就是,我們就說一般的草卻,當作它的胃比較多
It's not like we have only one stomach, it has several stomachs
它不像我們整個只有一個胃,它有好幾個胃
Inside one of the stomachs, it has cells
其中一個胃裡面,它有細胞
Bacteria, Bacteria has this Bebais glucose dumpling in it
細菌,細菌裡面有這個貝巴伊斯的葡萄糖水餃
so it can break down this fiber
所以它可以分解這個纖維
So look at this food-based animal, after it eats the food
所以你看它這個食材性的動物,它吃了材以後
It will have a stomach left to grind it first
它會剩下一個胃裡面先把它磨
After grinding, then it will reflect whether there is
磨了之後,然後它會反除有沒有
It's the current that goes to the mouth, and then stirs again
它這個潮流跑到嘴巴,然後再攪一攪
Then it will swallow the stomach inside
然後它就會吞到裡面的胃去
That's it, that's why we're different
就是這樣,所以我們不一樣了
As soon as we ate it we went down a bit
我們一吃了就有一點下了
There is only one stomach, and their ingredients are different
就只有一個胃,它們的食材性的是不一樣
Another one that you often hear is keting seeds
另外一個各位常常會聽到的就是基丁籽
This ketone seed, usually in the false insect
這個基丁籽,通常在假蟲
There are fake worms in the empty worms
空蟲裡面有假蟲
or this crab
或者是這種螃蟹
or shrimp
或者是蝦子
There are a lot of these chitin seeds in this shell
這個殼裡面就很多這些基丁籽
So everyone is hearing that in the park
所以各位在聽說,在園區
science park
科學園區
It's really just that there are people who specialize in collecting these shells.
真的就是有專門在收這些殼
That is to say, you are the shrimp moon, and you are the meat inside
就是說你是蝦月,你是裡面的肉
leave me that shell
把那個殼剩給我
Designing hydrolysis tanks of the hundreds of liters
設計那種好幾百公升的水解槽
Then do hydrolysis
然後呢然後去做水解
I'll talk about it later
待會兒會講到
What will become of it when it is hydrolyzed?
水解了以後會變成什麼東西
Then you can listen to this fund word
那各位可以聽聽這個基金詞
It is grape goose
它就是用葡萄鵝團
Then it's all about the medical links
然後全都是對達醫事鏈結
So this place it links to
所以這個地方它所鏈結的
It is very similar to the cellulose you just mentioned
跟你們剛剛講的纖維素很像像
belong to this form
都是屬於這種形態
Then I will introduce to you
那接下來我要跟大家介紹
The third part is about
第三個部分就是有關於
Introduction of sugary health food and medicine
含糖的健康食品跟藥物的介紹
what about the first one
那第一個呢
I'm going to tell you about
就要跟大家介紹關於
Gule Shami
所謂的顧樂沙米
This is what I just said
這個東西就是我剛剛講的
Are you going to collect a lot of these shells, right?
你是不是會去收很多這些殼對不對
Then it hydrolyzes it
然後它把它做水解
it does hydrolysis what does it use to do hydrolysis
它做水解它用什麼做水解
with hydrochloric acid
用鹽酸
After the hydrochloric acid is hydrolyzed
那鹽酸水解了以後
These will also be hydrolyzed
這些也都會被水解掉
So what you get is
所以你得到的是
Salts of hydrochloric acid of grape goose
葡萄鵝團的鹽酸的鹽類
Then we measure this thing by
然後這個東西我們測以
Therefore, lacto acid shows that it is translated directly in English.
所以乳酷酸明它就直接用英文就直接翻
So lactoamine is translated into Gulesamin
所以乳酷酸明就翻譯成固勒沙明
I ask you classmates
我問你們同學同學
If we can be called Grape Anton
我們如果可以稱呼是葡萄安唐
heart nothing special
心臟沒有什麼特別
the problem is here
問題是在這裡
gluxamine
這個固勒沙明
it's in the blood
它在血液裡面
It's the same as glucose
它也是一樣跟葡萄糖一樣
It will combine with the Nido Tree Society
它會跟尼島樹會結合
So if you say you have elders
所以各位如果說你有長輩
So someone is taking Gulesamin
所以有人在吃固勒沙明
You should pay attention to whether you have diabetes yourself
你要注意你自己本身有沒有糖尿病
because it goes the same way
因為它一下去也是一樣
we eat glucose
我們吃葡萄糖就是
like your blood sugar
就像你血糖
High glycogen levels in the blood
血液裡面的血糖原度升高太多
Because it's the Nido tree that's going to combine with it
因為就是尼島樹要去跟它結合
this too
這個也是
This man is actually exactly the same
這個做人的其實是一模一樣
So if you take Gulesamin
所以各位如果吃固勒沙明
be very careful
要特別小心
Just be careful with diabetics
就是有糖尿病患者會特別小心
The problem is below here
問題是在下面這裡
Because of this Gulsamin
因為這固勒沙明
It is said that the market has hundreds of millions
市場聽說有好幾億
So everyone has gone to that mass factory
所以各位都有去那個大量廠
because it's a bunch of
因為這是一堆
we want it to use
我們希望它用
Is this thing useful?
到底是這個東西有沒有用
Can it really improve joints?
真的能夠改善關節嗎
I don't think anyone has tried this either
我覺得這也沒有人試過
Everyone says we've used a lot of experts
各位都說我們有用過很多專家
In fact, the answer we got
其實我們得到的答案
The poop tells us it's a placebo
大便都告訴我們說是安慰劑
It is what Master often said, peace of mind will bring peace
就是師父常講的心安就會平安
Do you think it's useful if you eat it
你覺得你吃了覺得有用
it will be fine
它就會好
this is sometimes in my heart
這個有時候心裡的
This idea is also important
這種意念也很重要
but true is not valid
但真正的是不是有效
Everyone, it's theoretically like this
各位它的學理上是這樣的
It is wished to say that you ate this Gule Shami
它是希望說你吃了這個顧樂沙米
Then your body will synthesize
然後你身體會深合成
right
對不對
then you deep synthesis
那你深合成
deep synthesis of something
深合成什麼東西
hyaluronic acid
就是玻尿酸
right
對不對
Hyaluronic acid is hot right now
玻尿酸現在很熱門
you want to wrinkle
你要除皺
or to
或者是要
inside our eyes
我們的眼睛裡面
That's our Bo Li translation called hyaluronic acid
那是我們的波離譯叫波尿酸
Is the surface of our eyes smooth?
那是我們眼睛表面是會光滑嗎?
Right?
對吧?
That's hyaluronic acid in it
那是裡面的波尿酸
Our knees should be lubricated
我們的膝蓋這個要潤滑嘛
So this hyaluronic acid is produced
所以會產生這個波尿酸
hyaluronic acid content
波尿酸分質量
it is a polymer
它是一個聚合物
The higher the quality, the better
分質量越高越好
because of its water absorption
因為它的吸水性
the highest moisture content
含水量那麼最高
You'll have to look it up on Wikipedia
你會有去維基百科一查
what hyaluronic acid
什麼東西的波尿酸
highest quality
分質量最高
Machine irrigation
機灌
machine irrigation
工積的機灌
The hyaluronic acid in it has the highest quality
那個裡面的波尿酸的分質量最高
Than you use the way I live
比你用我生活的方法
Than what planning method do you use
比你用什麼企劃方法
Chemical methods are even better
化學方法做的都還要來得高
But I need to say something like this today
但是我需要我今天這樣一講
don't want
不要
So we are going to be killed
所以我們工積都要被殺了
no inside most true
沒有裡面最多真的
then hopefully
那就希望說就是
We are all like this hyaluronic acid
我們都心而成像這樣波尿酸
but you can see
但各位可以看到
these hyaluronic acid
這個波尿酸的這些
It is the composition of putao acid sugar
是普陶酸糖的組成
One is putao acid sugar
一個是普陶酸糖
The other one is N to CG putao acid sugar
另外一個是N以CG的普陶酸糖
so if you really want to eat
所以你真的要吃的話
which one we will suggest you to eat
我們會建議你吃哪一個
eat this
吃這個
N to CG's Putao acid sugar
N以CG的普陶酸糖
because after eating it
因為它吃下去以後
will not immediately enter the degree
不會馬上進到學歷
Same as Putao
跟普陶糖一樣
To combine with Ijima tree
去跟伊島樹結合
this is what you need to prove
這個是你要證實的
so this
所以這個
Won't make you a problem with diabetes mellitus
不會讓你造成糖藥病這邊的問題
if say you want to eat this
如果說你要吃這個
if you think it's not enough
假如說你覺得不夠
you don't add this
你不要再加這個
because it forms sugar
因為它要形成糖
Yes need two sugar
是需要兩個糖
so many
所以很多的
now you go to that
現在你去看那個
The kind of biotech company that sells drugs
藥品賣的那種生技公司
start many recipes
就開始很多配方
Just the price of sugar
就這個糖價一些
Various recipes from companies other than their own
各種就不止他們自己的公司的配方
This is what it says
這個說穿的就是這樣子
It's that simple
就這麼簡單
So the main meaning is
所以主要的意思是
ornithium
剝鳥酸
The other one is that you usually put it in the advertisement
另外一個都是各位通常在廣告裡面
see the so-called gnosis polysaccharide
看到所謂的靈知多醣體
Especially the former Chinese anchor
特別是以前的中式的主播
Ms. Xuan Miyang
玄米陽女士
Advertisement of Grape Network, right?
廣告的葡萄網對不對
The polysaccharides that are also gnostic also eat a lot
那個也是靈知的多醣體也是吃的很多
Everyone, polysaccharides of Gnosis
各位 靈知的多醣體
How to kill cancer cells
如是來殺癌細胞
Polysaccharides do not kill cancer cells
多醣體不會殺癌細胞
Polysaccharides are what you need to be able to get into your gut
多醣體是需要你能夠進到你的腸
enter the stomach here
這邊進入胃
Then the water and blood components are made into smaller things like this
然後水血成分成這樣比較小的東西
and then to the intestines to stimulate your immune system
然後到腸這裡可以刺激你的免疫系統
Then your immune system goes to fight the cancer cells
然後你的免疫系統就去對抗癌細胞
So this thing itself will not kill cancer cells
所以這個東西本身不會去殺癌細胞
So please don't get it wrong
所以請大家不要把它弄錯
that this one
那這一個
polysaccharides
這一類的這個俱內的多醣體
mostly this kind of glucose
大部分都是這一種葡萄糖
Then practice it with Beda 1 3 1 3 sugar tip
然後以貝達1 3 1 3的糖尖件所練合
with practice it will work
練起來會成的
this is the most
這個是最多
This is the basic stock price
這個是基本股價
Usually there are some single tangs connected at the 6th place
通常在6號的地方會有連接一些單唐
It may be Grape Church, it may be Yuanzao Church, it may be others
有可能是葡萄堂,有可能是園藻堂,有可能是其他的
A variety of these possible single tangs
各種不同的這些可能的單唐
But so far, there is still no solution for this
但目前為止,對於這個還是無解
Why? Because what is the composition of these things in practice
為什麼?因為練習的這些東西到底是什麼一個組成
It's still unclear
到現在還是不是很清楚
This includes our dean, who is also working on this part
這個是包括我們院長這邊,也是有在做這個部分
There is another one that I want to mention to you is the so-called Gansu
還有一個呢,要跟大家提的就是所謂的甘肅
Gansu
甘肅
I'm doing it, if you have elders, if I'm doing some kind of chemotherapy
在做,如果說你有長輩,如果我在做一些那種化療
POTA is often used sometimes
常常有時候要用中的POTA
POTA sometimes goes to wash for a while
POTA那個有時候一段時間下去洗
why? because it clots the blood
為什麼?因為它血液會凝固
That's what you need to use for anticoagulation.
那這個就是要用抗凝血的東西
Gansu
甘肅
a lot of
很多
former Gansu
以前的甘肃
where are they from
都從哪裡來
mostly from the mainland
大部分都是從大陸
mainland
大陸
So before the mainland
所以以前大陸
Before 2008
2008年前
Who is the richest person in mainland China
大陸最富有的人是誰
It's for Gansu
就是賣甘肃的
Why
為什麼
Because the mainland has a population of 1.3 billion
因為大陸有13億人口
Do you know how many pigs he kills a day?
你知道他一天要殺多少條豬嗎
you know i'm here you wanna laugh
你知道我來你想笑嗎
He wants to kill tens of millions of pigs
他要殺好幾千萬條豬
These he put these fields
這些他把這些場
after receiving
收了以後
Then go get this Gansu
然後之後去弄這個甘肃
Year 2008
2008年
what's a problem
出了一個問題是什麼
He went to get this Gansu
他去弄這個甘肃
He adds other things to you in it
他在裡面給你添加其他的東西
that is
就是
there was a so-called
曾有所謂的
over-safety
over-safety的
contrading-safety
contrading-safety
that thing
那個東西
add that thing
添加那個東西
he's okay sometimes
他有的時候沒事
want to increase his weight
想要去增加他的重量
go bag that one
去兜那一件
Turns out that thing is responsible
結果那個東西有負責任
As a result, several people died
結果造成好幾個人死掉
So the United States is scared
所以美國就嚇到了
He specially went to their site to see
他就特別去他們的現場去看
You can see the power outage like this
你就看到現場是這樣子停電的
You are under GMP control
你就這個是GMP管制的
So the United States is scared
所以美國就嚇到了
So it becomes to say that from 2008 onwards
所以變成說從2008年以後
You want to buy Gansu again
你要再去買甘肅
otherwise you can't buy
不然你買不到
or low molecular weight Gansu
或者是低分子量的甘肅
can't buy now
現在都買不到
Why? Because I dare not enter
為什麼?因為又不敢進
so here
所以在這裡
Everyone see it
各位看到就是
Recently there are some
最近就是有一些
a dance hall
一個舞堂體
this dance hall
這個舞堂體
It is specifically used for anticoagulation
它專門就是用來做抗凝血用
This dance hall body is already a medicine
這個舞堂體目前已經是一個藥
already in the US
已經是在美國
or here in Europe
或者是歐洲這邊
already a drug
已經是一個藥
We were doing this first
這個我們先是有在弄
This one is selling pretty well right now.
這個目前就賣得蠻不錯的
its price is quite high
它的價格蠻高的
So now is to try to make it as low as possible
所以現在就是要盡量能夠把它的成本
able to evolve
能夠進化
In this case, I hope that in the future, it will be much better if we build our capital and get rich.
這樣的話希望未來如果說我們建本、起富就會好很多
This is a stage, a structure
這個是一個舞台、一個結構
It can be combined with MHCB so this single
它可以跟MHCB所以這個單百來結合
It can be used for anticoagulant effect
可以把它拿到抗凝血的功效
There are also some anticancer drugs that you often hear
還有大家常常會聽到的一些抗癌藥物
The most leading one is Xiao Hongmei
最領先的一個就是小紅美
everyone has heard
大家有聽過
Little Red Beauty is all cancer drugs
小紅美就是所有的抗癌藥物
Everyone in these classes can see that
這些類的各位看到就是
In fact, except for this ring
其實它除了這個本環
Three structures on this side of this ring
三個本環這一邊的結構
It is very important that it contains a sugar
很重要一點就是它含有一個糖
This candy also plays a very important role in helping you
這個糖也是幫你很重要的角色
We thus self-satisfy
我們從而本身撒明
This mainly means that this place is a flat structure
這個主要就是說這個地方是一個平面的結構
It will hack into BMA's Migel Roof
它會砍入BMA的Migel Roof
Larger ore finer places
比較大的礦細的地方
it will cut into that place
它會砍入那個地方
can then reach
然後可以達到
This anti-cancer effect
這個抗癌的這個功效
that thing
那這個東西
Belly is not small
腹中不小
so it's beautiful when you hit it
所以它一打起來很美
hair loss
掉頭髮
Vomit
嘔吐
These questions are often
這些問題都是常來
Everyone
那各位
recently
最近
many of these drugs
很多這些藥物
when you use that viz
當你用那個維茲
Just Liposome
就Liposome
to wrap this
去包裹的這個
the stomach will be much lower
就會腹中就會低很多
will reduce a lot
會降低很多
Then
然後
Vomiting will also be reduced a lot
嘔吐的現象也會降很多
so everyone
所以各位
Unfortunately, this old man doesn't have many copies.
很不幸的這個健老沒幾副
but you can discuss it with your doctor
但是你可以跟醫生商量
If the family can afford it
家裡經濟過得去的話
you can
你可以
Can use
可以用
hit this thing
打這個東西
will compare
會比
It's beautiful when you hit it directly
直接打起來很美
came much better
來得好很多
In addition, some anticancer drugs
另外還有一些抗癌藥物
like this is
像這個是
This Purel2
Purel2的這種
injection
注射劑
then these are
那這些都是
i have a lot of people bring it up
我有很多人提出來
that is
就是說
these cancer drugs
這些抗癌藥物
it's actually quite sugary
它都其實很有一些糖
help you get these candies
幫你把這些糖
to the doctor
給醫生
it won't work
它就沒有功效
So many people want to know what role this sugar stone plays
所以很多人要了解到這個糖石扮演什麼角色
Does it just increase solubility?
它只是增加溶解度嗎?
It's not that simple
好像也不是那麼簡單
So this is commonly used, this Cornia
所以這個是常用的這個康乃亞
There are also some antibacterial antibiotics
另外還有一些是抗菌用的抗生素
This is made with a lot of bacteria sugar men
這個是用很多像菌糖男性
This is specifically for the muddy urine system
這專門用在泥尿系統方面
To deal with that E. coli infection
對付那個大腸感菌感染的
And like mud urine male mud
還有像泥尿男性泥
These are very amine-based
這些都是屬於很有胺基的這些
antibacterial
抗菌
This is also used in our daily life
這個也是用在我們日常生活用很多
Ladies and gentlemen, where do you go for the medicine to see your ingredients?
各位你們去哪藥會看你那種成分嗎?
still don't understand
還是看不懂
I don't understand, I need to check
看不懂要查
The current Internet is too differentiated
現在的網路太分辨了
we both have to check
我們都要查
So you need to find out what ingredients are in the medicine you used
所以你用了什麼藥成分是什麼你要查
to know its side effects
才會知道它的副作用
This is all available
這個都是可以查得到
Another is the red cotton tree
還有一個就是紅棉樹
The red cotton tree is also
紅棉樹這個也是
So use a lot when you have inflammation
所以發炎的時候用很多
The same goes for everyone
那這個各位也是一樣
It also has these sugars here
它這邊也是都有這些糖
Then these sugars will go to the bacteria
那這些糖它會去放於細菌的
The drug is called RNA
藥物叫作RNA
and then to be aware of its growth
然後去意識它的成長
That's one of its effects
那這個是它的一個功效
Then there is another one
那還有一個就是
What you often hear is
各位常聽到的就是
third line antibiotics
第三線的抗生素
vancomycin
就是萬古梅素
Usually when you don't even have this antibiotic
通常你連這個抗生素都無效的時候
you probably want
你大概就要
just be right please
就要對拜託
because possible
因為可能
some derivatives of it
它的一些衍生
some other variants of it
它的一些其他的變形
If there is no more effective doctor
如果再沒有效醫生
it can't help
它就沒有辦法
So this is already the third line
所以這個已經是第三線
followed by antibiotics
然後後面的抗生素
this is the same
這個也是一樣
this antibiotic
這個抗生素
It also has the structure of these sugars
也是都很有這些糖的結構
And without this sugar
然後沒有這個糖的話
its efficacy will be listed
它的功效就會上市
And our common Chinese herbal medicine
還有我們常見的中草藥
You have heard of real herbs
真草藥各位都有聽過
that herb
那這個草藥
Many of them are fried or watered.
很多都是用煎的嘛 用水嘛
It doesn't have to be in the water to fry with water
用水去煎的是不一定要在水裡面
Why don't you drink it? There are a lot of things in it.
你去喝嘛 那這裡面很多都是什麼
all contain sugar
都是含有糖
Let me give you an example
那這個舉一個例子
The innermost example is hay
最裡面的例子就是乾草
hay
乾草
hay this
乾草這個
This is the main ingredient in it
這是它裡面的主要的成分
this is a special
這是一個特品
That is, we start from a sticker class
就是我們從一個貼類
There are also some sugary things over here
那這邊也有含有一些糖的東西
that at that time
那在那個時候
hay means
乾草就是說
Some cores for some antiviral aspects
一些抗病毒方面的一些核心
and some like cardiotonic
還有一些像強心劑
For us there is a so-called Bitutoxin
對我們從有所謂的Bitutoxin
This category belongs to Cde-Glycoside
這一類的呢 是屬於Cde-Glycoside
That is to say, it has a sterol
就是說它這邊是有一個固醇
sterols and then sugars
固醇類 然後再連接糖
This is blown from the flower of a plant in Africa
這個是從非洲有一種植物的花裡面去吹去
Then tell me you have a heart problem
然後就講說你有心臟問題的
if say you let breath
如果說你要讓呼吸
no way heart
沒有辦法心臟
the so-called master gill
就是所謂的主腮
Putting this disability is something that can be proxied
把這個殘性就是可以代理
Vasodilation
血管擴張
The above is about the general we common these
以上是有關於一般我們常見的這些
Introduction of healthy food or medicine
健康食品或是藥物的介紹
Then I'm going to talk to him a little bit
接著要來稍微跟他提一點點
glucose metabolism
葡萄糖的代謝
I won't go into the details of those
這個也不會去講很詳細的那些
step by step metabolism
一步步的代謝
Just to tell you in general
只是很一般性的來跟大家
let's make an introduction
來做個介紹
We ate the usual glucose
我們吃了常吃的葡萄糖
the most important thing is to do
最重要的是要幹嘛
is to be able to generate energy
就是要能夠產生能量
what is this energy
那這個能量是什麼
is our energy currency
就是我們的能量貨幣
That is ATP
也就是ATP
what is this
那這個是什麼東西呢
You can see that
各位可以看到就是
glucose
葡萄糖
Then essential oil glycolysis
然後精油糖解作用
Then get this row
然後得到這個排日水
then this is
那這個就是
No. 2 has a bottle of this acid on the same plane
2號有一個同機的這種瓶酸
Then what
然後呢
Its ATP can be converted into ATP
它這個ATP可以轉變成ATP
And here is its structure
那這邊是它的結構
Mainly
主要就是
Here are two bottles of acid
這邊是有兩個瓶酸
This side becomes three bottles of acid
這邊變成三個瓶酸
Then this ATP
那這個ATP
is what we call energy currency
就是我們稱為所謂的能量貨幣
It can be used to provide energy
它可以來提供能量用
that here
那這裡
Our glycolysis is also fast
我們的糖解作用也很快
In this ranking, there are basically hillside map letters that can be walked
這個排位的基本上有山坡圖信可以走
We normally take this picture letter of swimming
我們正常的都是走這個游泳的圖信
so it will go through the acid cycle
所以它會經過明明酸循環
Then finally mix carbon dioxide with water
然後最後把二氧化碳跟水
can then be discharged
然後可以排出去
If today, if you are relatively hypoxic
如果說今天如果說你比較缺氧
Then there is a chance that this will turn into halogen acid
那這個就有機會會轉變成鹵酸
vitamin brine
那在維生鹵
vitamin brine this side
維生鹵這一邊
it is without oxygen
它在無氧的情況下
it can turn it into an inch
它可以把它轉變成一寸
so here
所以在這裡
Often we will be assigned a
常常我們會分到一個就是
Why stay up late to practice books or play rehearsal
為什麼熬夜練書或是打排
you will feel hungry
你會有飢餓的感覺
Do you have
有沒有
Will it feel like this at the end
在最後會不會有這種感覺
It will be better
會好
This is actually
這個其實
Because our brains use a lot of energy
因為我們腦部要用到大量的能量
energy needed by the brain
腦部這邊所需要的能量
is to use sugar to hydrolyze acid
是要利用糖解酸
it is used very quickly
它是用很快的
our organs
我們的器官
Do our organs also need
我們的器官是不是也需要
But the energy our organs need
但是我們器官所需要的能量
Demolition is not required
不需要用彈解作用
Is there only one other mechanism for a carbonless bomb
是只有一個另外一個無碳彈的機制
Then if it's the bombardment
那如果是彈解作用
This is for your quick access to that energy
這個是要你的快速取得那個能量
So you find this place in your brain
所以你會發現你的腦部的這個地方
do it fast
做得很快
Because you have to think when you are full
因為打排滿要思考
other things to think about
另數也要思考
So this consumes quickly
所以這個消耗的很快
That's why you get this hunger feeling
所以你才會有這種飢餓的感覺
So it talks about how to break through this one
所以它講的是怎麼突進這一條
soon
很快
Then why do we exercise
那為什麼我們如果運動
after muscle exercise
肌肉運動以後
We sometimes get that muscle sore the next day
我們隔天有時候那肌肉會痠痛
Is there such a problem
有沒有這種問題
Then
然後
the next day it was
隔天的時候它是
The amount of oxygen in your thin stomach because of your muscular movement
因為你肌肉運動你細胃的氧氣的量性
just not enough
就比較不足
Insufficient
比較不足
then it produces lactic acid
然後它就會產生乳酸
So your muscle soreness is due to lactic acid
所以你肌肉的痠痛是因為乳酸的原因
So lactic acid is not a good thing
所以乳酸不是好東西
in the intestine will excrete your sugar
在腸會出出你的糖
That bowel will lactic acid quickly
那個腸會乳酸很快
right
對不對
so you'll see what you've got
所以你會看到自己有什麼突進
Going this way is more hypoxic and sugary, right?
走這個比較缺氧糖對不對
Did you ever drink alcohol when you were young?
各位小時候有沒有量過酒
people may have also tried
人們可能也嘗試過
Because when I was young, I often couldn't help measuring alcohol
因為小時候呢量酒就常常會忍不住
open it
打開看一下
see what happens
看一下會怎麼樣
you will run in with oxygen
你就氧氣就會跑進去
Then if you run in and drink, you will become something like that
那你跑進去酒就變成不成在那種什麼
that vinegar
那種醋
So the resulting wine is very sour
所以弄出來的酒就很酸味
what is the reason
那這個是什麼原因
It's because he walks this way
就是因為他走這個
Your current lip it will go further
你現在的這個儀唇它會進一步
it may be spring or alcohol
它可能是以泉或以醇
Then further oxidation becomes acidic
那進一步氧化就變成以酸
So when you measure wine, you measure it into vinegar
所以量酒就會量成醋
that this is about this
那這個是有關於這個
I'm going to introduce this side
我要來介紹的這一邊
Then I will introduce to you a little
那接下來要跟大家來稍微介紹
The fifth part is about this sugar on the cell surface
第五個部分是有關於細胞表面的這個糖
Some other biological tools
其他的一些生物工具
This side is more biased
這邊就比較偏向
A little introduction to glycobiology
偏向一點糖生物學這邊的介紹
what about here
那這裡呢
That's what we use the electron microscope lens
就是我們用電子顯微鏡頭
Then look at this section of the cell
然後來看一下這個細胞的這個切面
So here's the nucleus
所以這邊有細胞核
then lipid
然後細胞脂
that this place
那這一個地方
This place is called the membrane of the cell
這一個地方叫細胞的膜
You see a very deep black thing
各位看到一個很深的黑色的這個東西
This is like a layer of sugar
這個就是一層糖一樣
so-called sugar republics
就是所謂的糖共和分子
it's on the outside of the cell
它就是在這個細胞的外表
So what is the situation with this sugar republic molecule?
那這個糖共和分子是怎麼一個情況
It is a very simple deep synthetic soil
就是一個很簡單的深合成的土
For your reference
給大家當參考
this is our cell membrane
這是我們的細胞膜
There are many pores in our cell membrane
我們細胞膜上面有很多的孔道
water channel
水的孔道
tunnel of mudstone
泥石的孔道
what else is there
還有一些是什麼
Pores of the bladder
斑膀的孔道
This kind of tunnel
這種孔道
Then the sugar can enter the cell
那這個糖就可以進入到這個細胞內
in this cell
那這個細胞內
In addition to glycolysis
它除了進行糖解
Just like what I just said
就像剛剛講的嘛
will generate RTP
會產生RTP
generate energy these
產生成能量這些
In addition it can also be transformed into different these nuclear dry water
另外它也可以轉變成不同的這些核乾水
Snap rod, sorry, snap rod
彈合桿 對不起 彈合桿
What are these for?
那這些要幹嘛?
These are used to make the so-called sugar assembly
這些用來做所謂的糖的組裝
Then it can be used in high-quality subjects
那它就可以在高質課題
or internal fat pills
或者是內脂丸
this part of
這一部分的
Synthesize these Sugar Pound Whites right here
就在這邊深合成這些糖磅白
or candy paper
或者是糖織紙
that sugar pound white
那這個糖磅白
It depends on whether it is folded perfectly
它就要看它摺疊的有沒有完美
It doesn't work if it doesn't fold well
摺疊不好的還不行
Those perfectly folded
那摺疊完美的這些
With these candy papers it will
跟這些糖織紙就會
Run from this place to the surface of this cell
從這個地方跑到這個細胞的表面來
So you see that layer
那所以各位看到那一層
black is these things
黑色的就是這些東西
Sugar Woven Paper and Sugar Pound White
糖織紙跟糖磅白
Those things will age too
那這些東西也會老化
or poorly folded
或者是摺疊不好
Where does all this stuff go?
這些東西全部都會進到哪裡?
enter this media
進到這個媒體
It's like a hydrolysis factory in the media
那在媒體裡面就好像是一個水解工廠
it will rehydrolyze all these things
它就會把所有這些東西再水解
After hydrolysis, you will return to
那水解以後你就會回到
Back to Crown Sugar or Ankisu
回到冠糖或者是安基蘇
Then repeat the cycle again
那又再重複這樣的循環
So our cell factory is very
所以我們細胞工廠是很
So effectively it's doing this in a loop
所以有效率的它是一直循環這樣在做
it applies to every bit
它會應用於每一點一滴
it won't go to waste
它不會浪費的
So just look at the whole inside
所以就是要看整個的這個裡面
Like the people's body, do we have the annual certificate we just mentioned?
像人民體我們剛剛有講到的年隔堂證嗎
The annual certificate is in the people's body
年隔堂證就是在人民體裡面
Lack of this submerged coal
就缺乏這個水潛煤
that's a matter of genetics
那就是遺傳的問題
Then these sugar and molecules will be spread on the surface
那這些糖跟的分子它就會鋪入到表面
Then it will work with many foreign things
然後就會跟很多外來的東西會作用
including viral infections
包括跟病毒的感染
city ​​army infection
市軍的感染
or with some poison
或者是跟一些毒子
Poisonous mushrooms we often talk about
我們常常講的毒蘑菇
Ladies and gentlemen, do you get poisoned when you eat a lot of mushrooms?
各位很多菇類你吃了有時候會中毒嗎
or snake venom
或者是蛇毒
Bitten by a snake is not a venomous snake
被蛇咬到不是有毒蛇
These things will follow the superficial effects
這些東西都會跟著表面這些作用
So if you want to tell everyone in detail here
那各位如果說要這邊每一個詳細的跟大家講
probably another two hours
大概還要再講另外兩個小時
the virus here
這個病毒這邊
Let me give you a very simple introduction
跟大家做一個很簡單的介紹
Because this is related to our personal comparison
因為這個跟我們切身比較有關
Infectious diseases caused by viruses that are common in Taiwan
我們在台灣這邊常見的病毒引起的感染疾病
Including influenza virus, enterovirus, style stomach, cannon disease, infection virus
包括流感病毒、腸病毒、風格胃、炮癥、感染病毒
or pox etc.
或是陽痘症等等
Isn't it human? Yang will also
不是人嘛 陽也會
what about this
這個呢
about flu virus
有關於流感病毒
You can see that there is emotion
各位可以看到像情有感
or pigs feel
或者是豬有感
or people
或者是人
human flu
人的流感
Everyone
那各位
co-receptor
豬是屬於共同受體
it is
它是
and
跟
it is two
它是兩個
it can
它都可以
can infect it
可以感染它
So the problem that often breaks now is to say
所以現在常常會破壞的問題就是說
In the countryside
在鄉下
In the country you raise pigs
在鄉下你養豬
Do you know how to raise chickens?
是不是會養雞
Do you know how to raise ducks?
是不是會養鴨
so what
那所以呢
Then when the network rate is over, it will all be mixed together.
那完網率的時候就全部都混在一起
So this is a comparison
所以這個是一個比較
big problem
比較大的問題
Therefore, when the network rate is completed, it is necessary to command
所以完網率的時候要去指揮
in the end is
到底是
human head
人頭
So it's going to be bad fuck right here
所以會不好操就在這邊
that's here
那在這裡
You can see this virus
各位可以看這個病毒
The surface of this virus has two very important methods
這個病毒表面有兩個很重要的辦法
One called Hemorrhidim
一個叫做Hemorrhidim
not right
不好對啦
Everyone, just remember the first word
各位只要記第一個字就好
is H
就是H
The other one is Memidis
另外一個就是Memidis
is what we call the hydrolase of the so-called stripping acid
就是我們稱為所謂的脫衣酸的水解酶
Didn't we just talk about stripping acid?
我們剛剛不是就講脫衣酸嗎
This specialized hydrolyzed stripping acid
這個專門水解脫衣酸
Don't carry them too much
這個你不要背他們多
Just don't recite N
你不要背N就好
So often a flu virus
所以往往被一個流感病毒
Influenza A virus infection
A型流感病毒感染的時候
The doctor has been talking about how much H is
醫生就一直在講到底是H多少
how much N
N多少
The same one
是一樣
The most recent one is H7N9
最近的一個就是H7N9
That changes every year
那這個每年都在變
Vaccinations are usually done every year
每年通常要做疫苗
Please guess for a year
請一年就要猜
How likely are you to guess correctly?
各位猜對的機率有多高
some are ok
有些是OK
Some can't guess
有些猜不到
Then sometimes it is because the map will be worn
然後有時候就是因為地圖都會擬佩
But you guys are saying this is
但是各位就是說這個是
how to say it
怎麼講就是
I think it has a pretty big effect.
我覺得是說有蠻大的一個功效
can do a defense
可以做一個運防
Then this Pingnan Wutian Forest
那這個平南烏天林
Can have 16 kinds
能夠有16種
Then to the last two years
然後是到最近的這兩年
only to discover the 17th
才會發現第17種
from that Australian bat
是從那個澳洲的蝙蝠
Australian bat
澳洲蝙蝠
The 17th species found in that bat
那個蝙蝠裡面所發現的第17種
Then your map has 9 types
那你們地圖這個就有9種
that here
那這裡
Listen a little bit to say that this virus
稍微聽一下就是說這個病毒
it
它
It will use this H on its surface
它會利用它表面的這個H
this protein
這個蛋白
with the sugar on the surface of our cells
跟我們這個細胞表面的糖
to act
去作用
There will be a four other action on its side
它這邊會有一個四別的動作
and then after that it will do
然後之後它才會做
Pendococcus
Pendococcus
then enters the cell
然後進入到細胞裡面
then copy after
然後之後複製
After copying, it will finally go out, right?
複製完了以後最後它會出去對不對
when it will go out
它會出去的時候
Everyone, it's the surface
各位它這個表面
We just talked about the surface of our cells
我們剛剛講到我們這個細胞表面
it has that shoulder
它是有那個肩體
will use it
會把它利用
So after the virus replicates and infects
所以這個病毒複製染出來以後
When he wants to walk out of history
他要有履歷史出去的時候
He can't go out in history
他履歷史不出去
he's going to do another move
他要再做一個動作
what action
什麼動作
It is to use the N we just talked about
就是要用剛剛我們講的那個N
that half white
那個半白
Put the penetrating doctor on the surface of this cell
把這個細胞表面的那個透醫生
cut off
給切掉
he will be released
他才會釋放出去
So now the source of many drugs
所以現在很多藥物的源方
passenger flu
客流感
these drugs
這些藥物
It's all about the N
都是針對本來講的那個N
the enzyme dedevelopment inhibitor
那個酵素去發展抑制劑
what does that mean
那什麼意思
That is to say, let you suppress N
就是說讓你抑制N
is to make it non-hydrolyzable
就是讓它不能水解
then let this virus
然後讓這個病毒
can stick to the surface of the cell
可以黏在這個細胞的表面
keep it out
讓它放不出去
Can't let it out
放不出去
further our giant cell
進一步的我們的這個巨式細胞
will come and cut it off
就會過來把它切掉
so right here
所以就在這邊
So this guest flu
所以這個客流感的這個
actually show you
其實就展示你
what we just said
那我們剛剛講的
What is the lean body on the surface of this cell
這個細胞表面的瘦體是什麼
That is to say, today is again
就是說今天又是
this kind of love
情內的這種
It is the link of the toy acid to the galactose which is Alpha 23
它是剛剛講的托義酸來半乳糖是 Alpha 23 來鏈結
So where do you pay special attention
所以各位特別要注意的是哪裡
is this place
是這個地方
It's Alpha 23 to link
它是 Alpha 23 來鏈結
what if it's a human
那如果是人呢
Man is Alpha 26 to link
人是 Alpha 26 來鏈結
So our upper respiratory system
所以我們的上呼吸系統
The chromophores on the surface of our cells are this
我們的細胞表面的色體是這個
So that is to say
所以也就是說
pigeon cold
鴿子感冒
you don't come up to talk
你不上來講
not contagious
不會傳染給人
Conceptually
理念上
but now
但是現在呢
always these viruses
永遠是這些病毒
it will start to mutate
它是會開始突變
those mutant viruses
那突變的那些病毒
It can recognize both the Alpha 23
它既可以識別這個 Alpha 23
It also recognizes Alpha 26
它也可以識別 Alpha 26
So when they both recognize Alpha 26
所以當它們都識別 Alpha 26
Our bodies experience panic
我們人體會很恐慌
because it's a vibes lawyer
因為這是一個共鳴律師
one does not know
一個不知道
Therefore, the human body's supernatural system has always been interested in it from the very beginning.
所以人體的靈異系統一開始都對它都
There is no way to prevent the epidemic from doing it
對它做的沒有辦法去防疫
Another long virus
另外有一個長病毒
The most frightening thing about the long virus is this type 71
長病毒現在最可怕還是這個71型
This is what we call the hand-mouth group
這個我們做的所謂的手口組
What about this? Internet teaching houses will remind children
那這個呢網網教房子上都會提醒小朋友
be sure to wash your hands
一定要洗手
Because this is eaten after dipping your hands in the cake
因為這個是手沾蛋糕以後吃下去
This virus can pass through the human stomach
這個病毒可以通過人的胃
will not die very powerful
都還不會死很厲害
Because Rui said it was sour
因為瑞說很酸
it won't die either
它也不會死
Then go to the intestine and then infect the child's intestine
然後就到腸之後再感染那個小孩子的腸
After the infection over there, it caused these so-called hand-mouth problems
那邊感染了以後再引起了這些所謂的手口組的問題
that's here
那在這裡
on our gut side
在我們的腸這邊
Some recent research I found
最近的一些研究我發現
It should be with #23
它應該是跟α23
The communities of these links are more related
鏈結的這一些的社體比較有關
And there's something personal about this official
還有一些私情關於這個官員
or
或者是
Dungeon fever virus can bubble umbrella or stomach virus
敦格熱病毒會泡傘或者是肚子的病毒
Hepatitis, everyone, is umbrella or Dungeness fever
各位肝炎或者是泡傘或是敦格熱
everyone is clear
大家都滿清楚的
In the past one or two years, there was no morel disease in the Qingjing Camp
前一兩年在清晶營場沒有發生羊肚症
So a lot of those sheep were killed
所以很多那些羊就被殺了
These viruses use heparin on the cell surface
這些病毒它都是利用細胞表面的肝素
You just mentioned heparin
各位剛剛有提到肝素
Heparin on the cell surface is a helper receptor
在細胞表面的肝素是幫助受體
to do the infection
來做感染的動作
for example
舉個例來說
This is the scar phlegm reflected by the lights
這個就是被燈都反出來的疤痰
Can be used as a host for Amanitavirus
可以作為泡傘病毒的設體
Here we actually have to develop the core instead
這邊我們實際上是有去開發核心反反而
Take a test with Master Zhang Yilang
跟張一朗師傅去做測試
Let's see that scar phlegm can prevent the infection of this umbrella virus
來看疤痰可以來阻止這個泡傘病毒的感染
Next, I want to introduce to you about the candy on the surface of the red snowball.
那接下來要跟大家介紹一下就是有關於那個紅雪球表面的這個糖
The first thing to mention is the discrimination of the water shape
第一個要提到就是有關於這個水形的判別
Everyone knows that the judgment of water shape is based on our
各位都知道這個水形的判別是依照看我們這個
What is the structure of the sugar that the homework needs to face?
作業要面的這個糖它的結構是什麼東西
Hit to identify very hard water
打去判別很硬的水形
The O-shape is the putan sugar that connects sugar to galactose and then to this N-tailed CG
O形就是連找糖連到半乳糖再連到這個N尾CG的普塔恩糖
This is O-shaped
這個是O形的
In addition to this fish, Type A also has a galactose with N-tailed CG added
A形除了這個魚還有多加了一個N尾CG的半乳糖
If it is V-shaped, here is a galactose
那如果是V形的呢這邊是一個半乳糖
So everyone can see that people with AV shape have both
所以各位可以看到就是AV形的人就是這兩個都有
AV-shaped people have both
AV形的人就是兩個都有
So the first one will be Hot Blooded
所以第一個會是熱血形
If your parents are both European-type, your child will definitely be European-type
你如果父母親都是歐型,你生小孩絕對是歐型
If one of your children today is type A or type D
如果說你今天生小孩有一個是A型或D型
Some family education came out
有些家庭教育就出來了
Another very important thing is that you read books, you must not learn from books
還有一個很重要的就是你書書,千萬不能書書的學型
how is this
這是怎麼樣?就是我們表現我是歐型
I have antibodies in my body, and I can accept European-type antibodies
我身體裡面有抗體,我是可以接受歐型的抗體
I will recognize him
我是會認他的
If it was said that your book was type A or type B that day
當天如果說你書出來的是A型或B型的話
Is there one more here?
這邊是不是多了一個
There is one more thing, can my antibody recognize him? No
多了一個東西,我這個抗體還能認他嗎?不行
so i bother you to take this for what ? foreign matter
所以我麻煩你當這個什麼?外來物質
i will attack him
我會去攻擊他
can't attack him
攻擊他就不行
That day I said you today you are type A
當天我說你今天你是A型的
You go to study European style
你去書歐型的學
Can this thing occupy his position?
他這個東西是不是可以佔據他這個位置
so it's ok
所以是OK的
Therefore, people of type A or type B can accept the learning of European people.
所以A型或B型的人都可以接受歐型人的學
But type A people cannot accept the learning of European type people.
但是A型的人不能接受歐型人的學
Because the two candies are different, right?
因為這兩個糖是不一樣對不對
Their sharp noses are unacceptable
他們鼻子尖是不能接受
who is the best
最好的人是誰
AV type people
AV型的人
AV-type people are often acceptable
AV型的人常常都可以接受
is his advantage
就是他的優點
you tend to go for some chemo
你往往去做一些化療
or do some combined treatment
或是做一些連累治療
Blood counts often drop to very low
常常會血球會降到很低
especially red blood cells
特別是紅血球
so inside the hospital
所以醫院裡面
Often an accepted Epo is used
常常會用到一個接受的Epo
Epo is a sugar pound white
Epo就是一種糖磅白
its a sugar pound white
它是一個糖磅白
Everyone see it
各位看到就是
This is NGIGON
這邊是NGIGON
There's another OGIGON over here
還有一個OGIGON在這邊
Currently this Sugar Pound White
目前這個糖磅白
know something
是有所知道的
For the past year around the world
目前全世界這一年來
I’m doing this for several popular settings
就熱門的幾個設置都在做這個東西
Because this year's market is also huge
因為這一個每年的市場也很大
Then several contacted scientists
然後幾個接觸的科學家
Now they are synthesizing this Sugar Pound White
現在都在合成這個糖磅白
It is the Epo who once learned
就是曾有學的Epo
Because what comes naturally is a mixture
因為從天然來的是一個混合物
everyone has been wanting
大家現在都一直很想
synthesize this pure thing
都合成這個純的東西
relatively controllable
比較能夠控制
Then this is a very popular molecule
那這個是一個蠻熱門的一個分子
The red snowball finished speaking
那紅雪球講完
Let me tell you about Snowball
接下來跟大家講白雪球
The white snowball is the initial step to our origin
白雪球是跟我們的發源的初始步驟
have a great relationship
有很大的關係
where is here
那這裡是在哪裡
That is to say, today our snowball
就是說今天我們的雪球
White snowballs in our veins
白雪球在我們的血管裡面
it's free
它是自由自在
it's free scrolling right
它在自由滾動對不對
then talk about it today
那今天講說
we have a place to shoot
我們有一個地方射傷
Then this shot will stimulate
那這個射傷就會刺激
will release this sieve
會放出這個篩球槛
Then it will let this blood vessel
然後就會讓這個血管
layer of cells
液的那層細胞
will express this so-called
會表達出這個所謂的
Our so-called Eselecting
我們這個所謂的Eselecting
Then this Eselecting
那這個Eselecting
I don't like how to divide
我不要中意怎麼分
It will be the same as the one on the white snowball
它會跟這個白雪球上面的這個
This Green Formula X with Cracking Acid
含有破裂酸的這個綠意式X
this sugar works
這個糖來作用
after that effect
那作用以後
will slow down the rolling of this white snowball
就會讓這個白雪球的滾動變慢
because it rolls freely
因為它本來自由自在的滾
Then there is interaction here, let it slow down
然後這邊有interaction,就讓它變慢
Slow down to what? Keep it from rolling
變慢慢到什麼呢?讓它不滾動
After not rolling, the white shoe ball can move from this
不滾動以後呢,這個白鞋球就可以從這個
gap between the cells of the blood vessel wall
血管壁的那層細胞的中間的縫隙
can pass through
可以穿過來
and get to this hurting place
然後到達這個受傷的地方
Everyone, come here with white shoes
那各位,白鞋球過來
it is the enemy also kill
它是敵人也殺
Your normal cells are also killed
你的正常細胞也殺
it doesn't recognize
它不認得
It is the killing of soldiers
它是群兵的殺
so it creates inflammation in your tissue
所以就會造成你的組織發炎
So the problem is here
所以問題就在這個地方
So this is a more professional
所以這個是一個比較專業的
Just take a look, everyone
各位看看就好了
That is to say this is
就是說這個是
The so-called very stripping acid
所謂的很有脫衣酸的這種
BV4X
BV4X
this four halls
這個四堂
Then follow the function of selecting
然後跟selecting的這個作用
Then this is just a show
那這個只是秀一下而已
What is the most important thing?
最主要是什麼?
How do you know if you have inflammation in your body?
你怎麼知道你自己體內是不是有發炎現象
The most important thing that doctors usually tell you to go
醫生常見的最重要就是要叫你去
Did you draw blood?
抽血有沒有
Going to measure the amount of your white snowball
要去測你的白雪球的那個量
what is the main thing
那這個主要是什麼呢
It's our White Snowball's tactic
就是我們的白雪球的戰術
win with more
就是以多取勝
so when you have an inflamed place
所以當你有一個發炎的地方
it produces a lot
它會產生很多
before being able to come
然後才能夠過來
then deal with it
然後去對付它
So when you draw blood and test
所以當你一抽血一測
Your white snowballs are relatively high
你的白雪球的量比較高
The doctor will tell you that your inflammation
醫生就會告訴你你的發炎
Is it this way
是不是這樣
This is seen in this way
這個是用這樣來看的
what happens to your doctor with inflammation
那你有發炎的醫生就會怎麼樣
give you antibiotics
就會給你抗生素
will let you kill the bacteria
就會讓你去殺那個菌
But everyone, if you kill the bacteria today
但各位如果今天殺了菌
If it belongs to this
如果說是屬於這種
this kind
這種
Gram-negative of this
Gran-negative的這種
Bacteria
Bacteria
Ladies and gentlemen, if you have a body with a lot
各位你如果有一個身體很多
bacteria
細菌
Bacteria have to protect themselves too
細菌也要保護它自己
So it's good for you to resist the crispness
所以你抗酥下去也好
Are the bacteria dead?
細菌是不是有死掉
right
對不對
So when it dies it will release
所以它死掉它也會放出
It's a cell currency thing, right?
它細胞幣的東西啊對不對
The most important one of the plaques of the cell currency is this
細胞幣的斑原最主要的一個就是這個
We call the so-called Lipid A
我們稱為所謂的Lipid A
Limb A
肢子啊 A
This thing is poisonous
這個東西很毒啊
very poisonous
很毒啊
so some people say
所以有些人說
Some people ask what causes scurvy
有些人會問造成什麼壞血病
That's where Yuanzong comes from
就是元宗都來自於這個
so you see diabetics
所以你會看到糖尿病患者
How did you die in the end?
最後怎麼死掉
it's all because
它都是因為
Because Mosha's nerve circulation is bad
因為莫莎神經循環不好
then black it out
然後就黑掉嘛
Then fattening
然後要結脂嘛
Then there's the bacterial infection
然後之後就是細菌感染
Bacterial infection ends up with acute sepsis
細菌感染最後都是急性敗血症
Nine and a half out of ten
十個有九個半都是這樣
so it's really
所以它真的
this is torture
這個是很折磨的
so you're talking
所以你在講說
this chronic disease
這種慢性疾病
Diabetes is the worst kind
糖尿病是最不好的一種
because its whole process is like this
因為它整個的過程就是這樣
That heart attack is the fastest
那心臟病最快
No, just leave, just leave
不行就走了就走了
That high blood pressure is usually treated
那高血壓通常都治療了
companies should know
公司應該知道
Mostly okay
大部分都還好
So be careful with diabetes
所以糖尿病真的要很小心
In addition, there are some who are born with us
另外還有一些是跟我們這個生育
The one that has a lot to do here is
這邊有很大的關係的一個就是
Sperm and primordial union
精子跟原始的結合
This place also has this identification cleared to this sugar
這個地方也有清理到這個糖的這種識別
mainly here
主要是在這裡
This is a mother's eye
這是一個母親的眼
There are some membranes on the surface
這外表是有一些膜
A special area we call ZP
特別一個區域我們稱呼為ZP
this area
這個區域
This region contains some proteins
這個區域有一些蛋白
what about the protein
那這個蛋白會怎麼樣
It will recognize the sugar on the surface of the sperm
它會去識別這個精子表面的這個糖
identify sugar
識別糖
Then its sperm can stick to it
然後它這個精子才能夠黏上來
after sticking
黏上來以後
Wait until the sperm enters and combines with sugar
等到這個精子進入以後跟糖結合
It's like combining with this dye
等於跟這個染結合
it emits some grainy stuff
它會放出一些顆粒狀的東西
will become the protection of the community
就會變成保護這個社群染
no more sperm
不會再讓其他的精子
Just don't allow this other sperm to come in again
就是不要可這個其他的精子再進來
So this is a process for the whole community
所以這個是整個社群的過程
so here
那所以在這邊
There will be a very important role in the identification of this sugar
就會有一個很重要的一個這個糖的一個識別的作用
and some are
還有一些是
I just found out about this polar region
我剛剛也知道這個極地
It is the fishes of Benshi and Antarctica
就是本石、南極這些魚類
these things
這些東西
Is it cold over there, everyone?
各位那邊是不是天氣都很冷
not like us
不像我們
Our Australia is in the thirties
我們的澳洲是在三十幾度
So this tree can be done at more than 30 degrees
所以這個下樹做到三十幾度
But what if the temperature is as cold as that
但是如果像那麼寒冷的溫度下怎麼辦
So these fish are also very powerful
所以這些魚它也很厲害
it developed the so-called
它發展出了所謂的
Anti-Dynamic Eggs
抗動糖蛋蛋
What about these anti-glycan eggs?
那這些抗動糖蛋蛋
it can protect them
它就可以來保護它們
keep it still
讓它不會動住
so it's that
所以它的那個
Down the tree can also be effective
下樹還能夠有功效
then next
那接下來
Now let me introduce
現在來跟大家介紹
about this
有關於這個
Useful plate-based anti-cancer
有用盤為主的這個抗癌
or a vaccine against infectious agonists
或者是抗感染性激動的疫苗
Just now the vice president mentioned at the beginning
剛剛副院長一開始開場的時候有提到
That is, generally speaking, vaccines are used against those who seem to be infected
就是一般來說疫苗都是用來對抗好像有感
How can it be used to fight cancer now?
那現在怎麼會拿來要去對抗癌症
even say there are other
甚至於說還有其他的
this new disease
這個感染新疾病
So today’s relationship at this time is going to give three simple examples.
那今天這個時間的關係要去舉三個簡單的例子
Come for your reference
來跟大家做參考
The first one is milk film and vaccine
第一個就是奶膜也疫苗
This is currently approved by the FDA
這個是目前已經是 FDA 也通過的
here in north america
在北美這邊
what is it for
它就是用什麼
Is it possible to use the so-called Tupanic acid we just talked about?
用這個我們剛剛講的所謂的拓疫酸有沒有
It uses this macrotonic acid
它是用這個巨拓疫酸
the vaccine
所去做的那個疫苗
This one is used against this
這個是用來對抗這個
Milk film and vaccine
奶膜也疫苗
So you can see that
所以各位可以看到就是
Normal milk film looks like this
正常的奶膜是這個樣子
Then when it becomes inflamed
那當它有發炎了以後
this place is going to get serious
這個地方就會變得很嚴重
Then this is the tonic acid that can be used
那這個就是可以用這個拓疫酸
What Fenggang mentioned just now is the so-called anti-cancer vaccine
剛剛風港提到的就是所謂的抗癌疫苗
Anticancer vaccines are like this
抗癌疫苗是這樣
the first is
第一個就是
It belongs to this kind of WC
它WC 屬這種
That and the Philippines
那和菲律賓這一類的
these so-called
這些所謂的
cancerous
癌癌的
anticancer
抗癌
This is a lot of these sugars on the surface of R cells
這是R細胞表面這些糖比較多
and some are very special
而且有些是很特殊的
Only cells directly above a certain I
只有在某種I正上面的細胞
for these antigens to exist
才會有這些抗原存在
The most famous one is Robo H
最有名的一個就是Robo H
Robo H is a sugar qualification belonging to Robocerease
Robo H這個就是屬於Robocerease的一個糖資質
And this one is about fighting breast cancer
那這個呢是對抗乳癌方面
Then this Robo H is 6 sugar
那這個Robo H是6個糖
Then this side is called Linus Serumis
然後這邊叫Linus Serumis
is a Lipetrin
是一個Lipetrin
but here they are now
但是這邊他們現在
Because this is on the surface of the I cell
因為這個是在I細胞表面
unique to the surface of primary I cells
主I細胞表面所特有
So I want to say that there is something special about
所以想說有個特異的就是
remove this place
把這個地方給移除
Then this place goes to connect a
然後這個地方去連接一個
a so-called carrier protein
一個在這個所謂的載體蛋白
Then use a carrier protein like this
然後用這樣的一個載體蛋白
After connecting this sugar with 6 sugars
連接了這一個6個糖的這個糖以後
it can go to induce its that
它可以去induce它的那個
body antibodies that can then come to recognize it
身體抗體,然後可以來識別它
Recognizing it can indicate that you have cells other than
識別它就可以表現你有以外的細胞
Its antibody will specifically fight against this
它這個抗體就會專門去對抗這個
Currently, this is in the third phase of clinical trials in Taiwan.
目前這個是在台灣有在做臨床第三期
Now do the third period
現在做第三期
We're going to see if we can succeed
我們要進一步看看是不是能夠成功
In addition to this, there is another type of Ganglion series we call
除了這個以外,還有另外一類我們稱呼的Ganglion series
This category belongs to the second category, and also belongs to this
這類是屬於第二類,也是屬於跟這個
bladder related
膀有關的
There is another one that belongs to the Lactose series
還有一個是屬於Lactose series
So these different bladders
所以這些不同的膀
its in different cancer cells
它在不同的癌細胞
It all has different amount of rendering
它都有不同的呈現的量
Another one is the so-called anti-inner ridge
還有一個就是所謂的抗內脊
Development of vaccine against spinal cord
抗內脊疫苗的開發
At present, many of these groups are studying
目前也是有很多的這些組在研究
This is mainly for what we call the so-called
這個主要就是針對我們稱呼所謂的
It's GPRN, it's the staff members of these five churches who have base eyes
就是GPRN可,就是這種有基存眼神的這些五個堂的當員
Then go to develop, to fight against this bad deed
然後去發展,要來對抗這個劣跡
That is also currently under development.
那這個也是目前正在研發的
It's finally the seventh
終於講到第七個了
This one is about Tanghe philosophy
這個是有關於堂跟哲學的一個
a personal servant
個人的一個伺候
Everyone because in this academic research
各位因為在這個學術研究
Often we just sometimes run into the fact that we have geometric layers
常常我們就是有時候會碰到我們有幾何層
When Teacher Liao Juncheng taught us before
以前廖俊成老師教我們的時候
The first one, the first thing I thought of was carbon six four
第一個,第一我想到就是碳六四
This is because the speaker in Germany is a football player
這個因為德國那對講的,是足球員
So this is a thoughtful molecule, everyone knows
所以這個是有心思分子大家都知道
I didn't just talk about the structure of a hall
我剛剛不是講一個堂的結構
Is this the expression
是不是用這種表達方式
Then we have a plan
那這我們有計畫學
There is a class of artistic molecules that is your link pill
有一類的藝術分子就是你一個環節丸
How do you connect it with another link pill with a carbon carbon piece with a big V?
你跟另外一個環節丸你怎麼樣用一個大V的碳碳件把它連起來
If you can connect, then this is an artist
你如果連得起來那這個就是一個藝術分子
Yes or no
是不是
Look out, friends
各位朋友小看喔
This kind of artist so far only has this
這一類的藝術分子到目前為止只有這個
Quads of this we're after QBEN
四邊形的這個我們之後QBEN
This one was made by a synthetic chemist
這一個有被合成化學家做出來
This is done by a professor from the National Education University
這個是自教科大學一同教授做的
the best
做得最好的
other these
其他的這一些喔
3 sides, 5 sides, 6 sides, 7 sides, a little bit of this can't be done
3邊5邊6邊7邊點點點這個都做不出來
so far
到目前為止如解喔
Then this is a big challenge for us to synthesize
那這個就給我們做合成的有一個很大的挑戰
Then I feel very inaccurate
然後也覺得很不準喔
But I'm thinking that my genetics can't change
但是我在想說我這個有基因化學變不出來
can i use another way
我是不是可以用別的方式
Then you see
那各位看到就是
We all figured out how to make this carton paper
我們都想辦法去做這個紙盒紙
See if we can make hexagons because of this need
看是不是因為這個有需要我們可以做六邊
Our height can vary
我們這個高度可以變化
Then the pattern above can be changed
然後就上面的這個花樣可以變化
then here everyone
那在這裡各位
my personal feeling
我個人的感覺
we do bomb science
我們做彈科學
it's sweeter
就比較sweet
then origami is fun
然後折紙就是樂趣
Origami is like doing research
折紙跟做研究一樣
each different shape
每一個不同邊形
The length of its side is related to this
它的這個邊的這個長跟這個關係
Still need some math to understand
還是需要用一些數學去了解
So three sides, four sides, five sides
所以三邊、四邊、五邊
Different polygons have different relationships
不同邊形有不同的關係
Then this is a triangle relationship
那這個是有一個三角關係
that's ok
那就可以
A piece of paper can fold a fit
一張紙就可以折一個合身
Another piece of paper can cover a box lid
另外一張紙可以遮一個盒蓋
we can shade various polygons
我們就可以遮各種不同邊形
Everyone, this kindness
這位各位這個溫馨
I also spent ten years
也是我花了十幾年
just got it out
才把它弄出來
Now you can do all kinds of different polygons
現在可以做各種不同邊形都可以做
in theory
理論上
Can also do 7, 8, 9, 10
也可以做7、8、9、10
Samples I can bring today
我今天可以帶來的樣品
that is
就是
this is carton paper
這個是紙盒紙
means you can open
就是說你可以打開
a box body
一個盒身
The other is the lid
另外一個是盒蓋
Then there can be different polygons
然後可以有不同邊形
I brought three today
我今天帶了三個
Two to three, our vice president
兩個要三個我們副院長
668 orders
668順
Thanks
謝謝
Another one I'm of course leaving me with a question
另外一個我當然要留給我有一個問題
I want to ask everyone
我要請教大家
Give him the right answer
答對的這個就算給他
so when there is a problem
所以當有問題的時候
so this is
所以這個是
I personally think that this is a
我個人覺得說這個是一個
to the elderly
對老人家
You can watch your Mosha nerves
你可以細心你的莫莎神經
This change above is something you can think about every day
這個變化上面這個是每天可以去思考
So I think the problem that the old people have now
所以我一覺得現在老人吃到的問題
more and more
越來越多
this is a pretty good one
這個是一個蠻不錯
so everyone
所以各位
What you see here are a few simple
這邊你所看到是幾個簡單的
you know i have done all kinds of different
你知道我有做的各種不同
I have printed it out
我有把它印出來
There are some
有一些
You are also interested
你也有興趣啦
you are interested to see
你興趣要看
I've been wanting to say
我現在都一直想說
Publisher of our hospital
我們醫院的出版社
It's all about literature
好像都是出文學方面的
can you say this
可以說這個嗎
i never knew
我一直不知道
because i do science
因為我做科學
I never dared to ask
我一直不敢去問
Because I'm afraid of being talked about by the hospital, it's not as good as a job
因為怕被醫院講說也不如正業
I want to say am I
我想說我是不是
You can use Saturday and Sunday
可以利用禮拜六禮拜天
want to say half water
想說半水
so those outside
這樣外面那些
Amount that can sell this paper
能賣這個紙的額子
But it seems that it is not bad to ask for a piece
可是好像也還不錯的要一塊
yes, this is
對,這個就是
I'll see how it works as soon as I talk
我一講就看怎麼樣是不是能夠
A book that can be covered first
能夠先出一本遮紙的書
this is my current wish
這是我目前的願望
but because it has been
但是因為一直
It's ugly like I took it
像我拍的就拍得很醜
If you look at the picture they took
如果看他們拍的那張
you can take beautiful pictures
就可以拍得很漂亮
that this is a person
那這個是個人
a purely personal interest
純粹個人的一個興趣
so i conclude
所以我總結
what we are talking about today
我們今天講的這個
seven themes
七類的主題
and then
然後就是
From the general introduction to the final
從一般的介紹一直到最後的
This masking aspect
這個遮紙方面的
that this
那這個
I finally want to thank you
我最後要感謝各位
listen very patiently
非常耐心的聽講
Because it's really a cold scene
因為這真的是一個很冷場
one and a half hours
一個半小時
So if there are two slides
那如果有兩張投影片
want to share with you
想要跟大家分享
that one is
那一個呢就是
Qipenjiao
七盆腳
this is
這個是
Our Ziyi State Security Officer in Taiwan
我們台灣的子儀國保
thank you very much
非常謝謝各位
We walked in the courtyard of the old courtyard
我們走在院舊院的院區裡面
Is there an ecological stone opposite the Biochemical Institute?
生化所對面是不是有一個生態石有沒有
There was a chessboard corner
那裡竟然發現有棋盤角
checkerboard corner
棋盤角
Have you seen it?
各位有看過嗎
that's really beautiful
那真的很漂亮
and only open at night
而且晚上才開
It's like setting off fireworks when it's on.
開的時候真的是像放煙火一樣
So if you guys are going to end up walking over
所以如果各位有待會結束走過去
is it blooming now
現在有沒有開花
The other one is more special
另外一個是比較特別的
is a walker about this technological advancement
是有關於這個科技進步的一個行師
this is my personal feeling
這是我個人的感覺
Said a word to me Da Ying Shi Tan
對我大大英師坦講了一句話
He said he was hot on the day that technology will tear down the moon and human interaction
他說他很熱一句科技會拆月人類互動的那一天
The world will become the age of idiots
世界將會變成是白癡的時代
Guys, this thing is with us now
各位現在這個東西已經在我們的身邊
already found
已經在發現了
Regardless of the construction vehicle
無論動工車
regardless of writing luck
無論做寫運
Even from the MRT, from this line, you have to change to another line
甚至從捷運,從這一個線,要換到另外一個線
That person can still look down the stairs and up the stairs like this
那個人都還是可以看得這樣子下樓梯,上樓梯
I really admire him, he is not afraid to bump into
我真的覺得很佩服他,他都不怕會去撞到
Then this has become an eyeful
那這個已經變成一個滿眼中
When I formed that, what was it that I was discussing?
我當時形成那個,竟然在討論是什麼?
Discuss the so-called Internet idiom certificate
討論所謂的網路成語證
Then it's like taking drugs
然後要跟吸毒一樣
to that music venue
要到那個樂界所
can borrow
才能借
I've connected like this
我已經連過到這個樣子
So like we shared doing a lot of the same period of popular school avoidance
所以像我們分享做很多流行避學的同期
will happen in the next five to ten years
就會發生未來的五到十年
In the past two years, I heard that the ophthalmologist's life is very good.
這一兩年聽說眼科的生命就特別好
The glasses store sells a lot
眼鏡行就賣得特別多
What is the next one? The next one is avoidance
再來的是什麼?再來就是致避
Because that's what children face
因為小孩子面對的就是這個
I'm exaggerating a bit more, I also saw a mother pushing a music
我更誇張一點,也是我看到一個媽媽推了一個音樂
you are asleep
你睡了喔
In front of the music there is a
那個音樂的前面就擺了一台
He just touched there one by one.
他就一一的就在那邊摸啊
It's in there
一摄的就在那裡面
He slowly took one himself
他慢慢自己也拿了一台
I see it
看了我就覺得
how could he do this
他怎麼會這樣
this is really
這個真的是
i think
我覺得說
if i can't deny
我如果不可否認
Is the progress of the computer is really
就是電腦的進步真的是
very important nothing wrong
非常重要 沒有錯
but
但是
nothing is
也沒些東西就是
hope not to overdo it
希望不要用過頭
overused words
用過頭的話
Actually to the end
其實到最後
only our own body
才會到的是我們自己的身體
I want to share this with you
這個事我想要跟大家分享
thank you all thank you
謝謝大家 謝謝
We are very grateful to Professor Hong
我們很謝謝紅教授
Red Clear Rescue
紅分明救援
great introduction to us
跟我們很精彩的介紹
This Tang Dynasty is interesting
這一個唐人異趣
He today no matter from the scientific point of view
他今天不管從科學的角度
From an artistic point of view
從藝術的角度
Or from the perspective of disease prevention
或者從疾病預防的角度
from a therapeutic perspective
跟治療的角度
also give us a lot
也給我們很多
such a valuable knowledge
很寶貴的這樣的一個知識
actually listen to people
其實來聽人講
watch this with you
跟你看這個
iPhone iPad 3.0
iPhone iPad 3.0
that kind of thing is very different
那種東西是很不一樣的
is that we have good human-to-human interaction
就是我們有很好的人與人之間的互動
What about after the appointment?
那約講完了以後呢
Of course we also hope that everyone and our generals
我們當然也希望大家跟我們的將員
Have better Q&A interaction
有比較好的Q&A的互動
I don't know if you have any questions
不曉得大家有沒有什麼樣的問題
come to ask
要來請教
Haolai Zhou Yueqing
好來 周月慶
ask the professor
請教教授
Thank you so much
非常感謝
it was a very good speech
這是一場非常精采的演講
I come every month to listen to something as brilliant as this rarely
我每個月都來聽像這麼精采的很少
Thanks
謝謝
ask the professor
請教教授
my question is simple
我這個問題很簡單
and you please don't scare me
而且你請不要嚇我
but i want to know
但是我很想知道
The professor just mentioned dried inulin
剛剛教授有提到乾菊糖
That is to say, you eat the leaves and they are very sweet
就是說你吃了葉子就很甜
non-toxic and harmless
又無毒無害
can we use dried inulin leaves
我們可不可以用乾菊糖的葉子
In place of that sugar heaven
來代替那個糖天堂的用
is now used
現在是用
I think it should be possible now Tianju Tang
我是覺得應該是可以現在天居糖
In fact, in Japan or in the mainland, they have to extract
其實在日本或在大陸他們都有去萃取
I am selling this Tianjutang exclusively
我專門在賣這個天居堂
In Taiwan, you actually go online to report what happened in Tianjutang
台灣這邊其實你上網把天居堂生的事
You can also find agents
你也可以找得到代理商
So you can actually buy
所以實際上你是可以買得到
But that means the Department of Health may not have announced it positively.
但是就是說衛生署這邊可能並沒有很正面的去公佈
so that everyone can use more
就讓大家能夠多去使用
If you go to the flower market to buy leaves to eat
如果到花市去買葉子來吃
It's okay to be in the south
自己南方是可以
In fact, the sweetness is of course not as sweet as it is stored
其實那個甜度當然就沒有存的那麼甜
It means that if you eat it, you will feel a sweet taste in your mouth, there is nothing wrong with it
就是你吃的話會有感覺到嘴巴有甜味沒有錯
But it's not as sweet as extracted, isn't it?
但是沒有萃取的那麼甜是不是
Yes, what is extracted is what is stored
對 萃取的就是存的那個東西
Thank you and the second question
謝謝 還有第二個問題
It's the hay that your professor mentioned just now
就是你剛剛那個教授有提到那個乾草
So if hay is good for the body too
那如果說乾草對身體也很不錯
Buying hay flakes will make tea and you feel very dry
買乾草片會有泡茶和你覺得很乾
I am studying medicine myself.
這個我自己是學在醫的
Yes, because many people will talk about this balance
對 因為很多人都會講這個均稱
So I still suggest that you can ask a Chinese doctor to see
所以我還是建議你可以去問一下中醫師看看
Because it depends on your physique whether it is suitable for this kind of thing
因為要看你的體質 是不是適合這種東西
Because some people have different constitutions, some are hot and some are cold.
因為有的體質有的熱有的冷這些不太一樣
Thank you Jiaqi
謝謝家綺
ok who else
好 還有哪一位
come welcome sir please
來 歡迎這位先生請
sorry for the viewers
對 觀眾各位不好意思
Then I think that several years ago we read in a newspaper in Taiwan that
那我覺得在好幾年前我們台灣的報紙上有看到一個說
the british said to the newspaper
英國人就報紙說
There is a universal vaccine for influenza A
有找到一個A型流感的萬用型的疫苗
But when I saw that news about three or four years ago, there was no follow-up
可是那個新聞大概三四年以前我看到的時候就沒有後續
Then I think a question is to say
那我就想一個問題是說
All of the influenza A does it have some missing pieces
所有的A型流感它有沒有一些缺塊
It is an invariant and has antigenic properties
它是一個不一定不變的 而又具有抗原特性的
Then I don’t know you just mentioned that there are so many H and H and there are so many N
那我不知道你們在剛剛有提到H跟H有這麼多N有這麼多
and so much more
還有主要那麼多
Every now and then a new type A flu
三不五時跑去一個新的A型流感
We're scared to death
我們就怕得要死瘦不了
even water
甚至是水
It is possible that in the section of new material research
有可能在新資料研究的部分
Find books from the structure of carbohydrates
從糖類的結構去找書
Type A parts can
A型的部分可以
It can be said to be a marker for the basis of my vaccine development
可以說我疫苗開發依據的一個marker
If so, will something like this be developed in the future?
這樣的話是不是以後這樣東西開發出來
Don't be afraid of newcomers coming out
大家就不用怕新人冒出來
It's ok to call first
先打就ok了
so that's my idea thanks
所以是我的想法 謝謝
Thank you
謝謝你
Because it's everyone's dream
因為這個也是大家的夢想
I hope you can find the so-called
希望說你們可以找到所謂的
broad-spectrum vaccine
廣用型的疫苗
can beat everything
就可以打敗一切
words here
在這裡的話
Most of the previous research and development was aimed at
以前大部分的研發都是針對
You just talked about a half-blank paper here
你剛講半白紙這邊
So are you able to find
所以你講是不是能夠找到
a common sequence
共通的一個 sequence
you target that sequence
你就針對那個 sequence
is the development antibody
是發展antibody
make a vaccine
去做疫苗
This is the way it used to be
這個是以前的做法
Use this type to find
是用這樣子的型態去找
but that means
但是這樣就是說
Can cohabitation be found?
共居性是不是能夠找得到
Can do a better sequence
能夠做得比較好的 sequence
this is a problem
這是一個問題
Our dean is doing it
我們院長就在做了
Our dean and horse test
我們院長跟馬測
one of the things they do is say
就是他們有做的一個就是說
This Timaru Dilim
這個提馬魯迪林
He actually has a lot of these on the surface
他表面其實有很多的這些
N-Guy icon
N-Guy icon
They found that light
他們發現就是說光
If you come out like this
你直接如果是這樣子出來的
Go to indus N-Guy body
去indus N-Guy body
Because those N-Guy icons are big
因為那些N-Guy icon很大
or cover up
或遮住
will cover him
會遮住他
So that N-Guy body's
所以那個N-Guy body的
It's definitely not that good of a choice.
也肯定選就不是那麼好
the hydrolyzed protein
那個水解的蛋白
Those N-Guy icons cut off
那些N-Guy icon切掉
Cut off leaving only one sugar
切掉只留下一個糖
is the first candy
就是第一個糖
It's NGuy CO-Gay Glucosamine
就是N-Guy C-Guy的葡萄安糖
The sugar is still on the egg white
那一個糖還留在那個蛋白上面
They found that this is how
他們發現就是用這樣子的
Glycoprotein
糖蛋白
then that
然後那個
when antibodies come
抗體來的時候
it can
它可以
identifiable
可以識別的
Many antibodies recognize egg vesicles
很多抗體可以識別蛋泡
Such a glycoprotein
那這樣的一個糖蛋白
Today it doesn't matter how much H you are
今天就不管你是H多少
Many and few of those sugar egg lilies
許多少的那些糖蛋百合
Because Englekensla watch those many different
因為恩格來肯斯拉表那些很多不同嘛
But you cut off the exterior
但是你把外表的那些都切了
As long as the most basic sugar in it
只要裡面的最基本的一個糖的話
that's all the same
那是全部都一樣的
So they are developing now, that is to say
所以他們現在就是在發展就是說
Can this thing be made universal?
是不是這個東西可以變成是通用的
Universal's Vaccine
Universal的Vaccine
This is what our dean is currently doing with that teacher Ma Fang.
這個是目前我們院長跟那個馬側老師在做
Well, of course everyone knows this.
那當然這個東西大家都知道嘛
You come out with a sexual concept of any thing
你任何一個東西一個性觀念出來
Then after many visual tests
然後經過很多觀的測試
I don't know if they have already transferred the record to the company
我知不知道他們是已經有記轉給公司啦
But that is to say, has it entered clinical trials?
但是就是說是不是已經進到臨床測試這一些
Might have to wait for further news
可能還要再進一步等待消息
After all, we hope that our dean will not be told by him
我們到底希望我們院長得沒有被他講啦
right
對不對
This is mainly
這個主要是
This is mainly to say that it really didn't work out.
這個主要是說真的沒成功
Definitely not mentioned by him
絕對是沒有被他講起的
I can tell you like this
我可以這樣子跟你們預告
But this thing just takes time
但是這個東西就是還要時間
we're going to push
我們要去推動
good
好
come to a mirror
來個鏡
May I ask why the cranberry has no effect after adding Liposong?
請問一下小紅莓為什麼加了Liposong之後就比較沒有附作用
I found it on two roads, but I don't know how, it is the benchmark of its function
我是在兩路上查到,但是我不曉得怎麼樣,就是它的作用的基準
Because of course it is possible to bring this little Ami's comparative comfort
因為當然它是可以帶這個小阿美的比較舒適性
So it can be packaged by Liposong, so it can be brought in
所以可以經過Liposong的包裹,可以讓它可以帶進去
In Taiwan, I know a company that is doing Weiss, and now the stock has been rising recently
在台灣我知道做維斯體的公司,現在最近股票一直上揚
Because it is the part of the application that seems to be pretty good
因為它就是這個部分的應用好像蠻不錯的
But I don't know the real function benchmark, sorry
但真正的作用基準我比較不懂,不好意思
Don't forget I just had a question for you guys
各位不要忘記我剛剛有一個問題來問你們
If you have any questions, we will ask Teacher Hong to ask questions
如果大家有問題的話,我們就讓紅老師來問問題
He will give you this beautiful elbow
他會送你們很漂亮的這個肘子
May I
可以嗎
still have a question
還有一個問題
i'm not a problem
我不是問題
I also want to add to what I just said about Liposong
我也是補充一下剛剛講的Liposong
Because someone who supplements Liposong will receive cancer cell
因為有人是補充Liposong比較會接到cancer cell
Less likely to receive normal cell
比較不會接到normal cell
Because many neuroparticles have this characteristic
因為很多neuroparticle都有這種特性
Then if he does not receive normal cells
那他如果不接到正常的細胞
It will have fewer side effects
他副作用就會比較少
Thank you for our director's supplement
謝謝我們主任的補充
this is a very important thing
這是一個很重要的事
Come on, demonstrate a problem
來,示範一個問題
I'm curious
我很好奇
Talking about the C2 acid of poisonous starch
講到毒澱粉的順滴C2酸
followed by back dripping C2 acid
跟著反滴C2酸
Why add this dropwise C2 acid
為什麼加了這個順滴C2酸
what chemical reaction
是什麼化學反應
Let it taste more Q
讓它的吃起來會比較Q
what structure is causing this feeling
是什麼結構造成這種感覺
I didn't discuss this
這個我沒有去探討
I will ask the master who made this starch
會問一下做這個澱粉的師傅
Professor Wang
王教授
He has to apply for a patent
他有去申請專利
then later failed
然後後來沒有通過
These are the best
這些滿最好
if pass everywhere
如果到處通過的話
This is terrible
這下不得了
the reason behind this
這個後面的那個原因
I didn't show up first
我是沒有先出面
yes
是
ask a question
請教一個問題
even if it makes sense
就算這個東西有道理
how bad
有多壞
I seem to see it now
現在好像看了
Eating naked eyes is like being completely dead
吃肉眼就像全死的樣子
Some so-called over-standard
有些所謂過標
But what about passing the bid?
但是過標議會怎麼樣
Are you going to do good?
你都要去取善嗎
this is
這個是
Of course, there is an announcement from the Department of Health
當然衛衛生署這邊是有公告
That is how much weight per day
就是說每天多少體重的
probably can say
大概是可以講
how much is that
那到多少
But I feel that is the highest standard
但是我感覺到那個都是最高標
but everyone
但是各位
There are always several kinds of food you eat every day
你一天吃個食物總會有好幾種
But so many additions
但是這樣很多的添加物
a lot of these
很多這些
This is not the only one
這樣都不只那一個
so here
所以在這邊
In fact, if you are outside
其實各位如果在外面
can buy books
都可以買得到書
so-called food additives
有所謂的食品添加物
Have you seen this book
各位有沒有看到這種書
there is a japanese
有一個日本人
So inside the job ended up he wrote a book
所以裡面工作最後他寫了一本書
is the thing that unmasks these food additives
就是揭開這些食品添加物的東西
this word is
這個的話就是
at present
就是以目前
That is to say, poison experts on the side of Long Roots.
就是說以長根這一邊的毒物專家
what he did he did with that animal
他做的他是拿那個動物去做的
He found out that he was not good for his kidneys
他發現是說他對腎不好
It's not good for the kidneys, so he concluded that
對腎不好所以他就歸納說
If you take too much of this stuff
這個東西可能對腎吃過量的話
permanent damage to the kidneys
會對腎會有永久性的傷害
That's why he proposed that he would do kidney dialysis
所以說這樣他才提出說會洗腎
But our Sun Yuxuan
但是我們的孫玉璇
Dean's daughter Sun Yuxuan
院長的女兒孫玉璇
Professor Sun Yuxuan
孫玉璇教授
He is a professor at the National Taiwan University Laboratory
他是台大實驗所的教授
He brought up another one that he felt
他就提出了另外一個是覺得說
That is the difference between animals and people
那個是動物跟人不同
So people's words don't seem to be that serious
所以人的話好像沒有那麼嚴重
So he thinks that further research is needed
所以他是覺得說還是要再進一步的研究
Let's see if it's really possible
去看是不是真的能不能這樣
right
對
but still
但是還是
always more than a word
總過於一句話
I feel like saying
我就覺得說
many things should not be added
很多東西不應該添加
should not be added
就不應該添加
But the manufacturer is
但是廠商他就是
want to make money
想要賺錢嘛
so he'll add these things
所以他會加入這些東西
But I feel like saying
但是我又覺得說
our government
我們的政府
we are sometimes
我們有些時候就是
Tai easy compromise
太容易妥協
just by you
就被你說
in order to compromise
為了要妥協
is about to become a
就要變得一個
The so-called allowable range
所謂的容許範圍
This makes people feel
這個就讓人家覺得
doesn't seem so good
好像不太好
because of that tolerance
因為那容許範圍
it will sometimes be blurry
就會有時候會有模糊
So like social gold
所以像社會的金
Originally it was fixed and could not be added
本來是固定不能添加
what's going on now
現在變怎麼樣
How many PPTs are available
多少PPT人家都可以
right
對不對
Is that mountain giant Qingan there?
那個山巨青安有沒有
Plasticizer
塑化劑
toxic starch
毒澱粉
Guess why next
各位猜下一個為什麼
Excuse me
不好意思
that's for the eyes
那是眼睛的
your eyes
你的眼睛
It's also easy to pick one by one
這也容易的去取一個一個來
So I think this is really a big problem.
所以我覺得這個真的是一個蠻大的一個問題
ok if there are no other questions
好 如果沒有什麼其他的問題
Let's now invite Professor Huang to ask us questions
我們現在來請黃教授來跟我們問問題
ok, simple question
好的 問的很簡單
Everyone, I just mentioned SARS, right?
各位我剛剛有講到SARS對不對
SARS outbreak expected in 2003
在2003年爆發SARS預期
This year is also a better tenth anniversary
今年也是比較好十週年
Did everyone forget
大家是不是忘記了
You said who has the government computer?
你說政府電腦有誰
Let's mention this matter
這就提這件事情沒有
but you know what
但是你知道嗎
Back in 2003 we were in front of the TV
當初2003年我們那時候就在電視前面
It was really troublesome at that time
那時候真的是人心煩惱
I don't know how you feel
我不曉得各位的感覺什麼樣
I saw a face at that time
那個時候就看到了一個臉孔
appear on tv
出現在電視上
then tell us this stuff
然後就告訴我們這個東西
How should you prevent
你該怎麼樣去防治
right, you should have a fever
對不對 你該你這個發燒
It's contagious because he has a fever, right?
因為他發燒才會傳染對不對
You can't go to public places, and you have raised the so-called 2 seconds to enter a public place, is that right?
你不能到公共場所,而且提出了所謂進入公共場所一定要2秒,有沒有?
At that time, Taiwan had the least number of hospital patients, and it was the cleanest time, because everyone wore masks, and it was really the best time
那個時候台灣的醫院病人是最少的時候,而且是最乾淨的時候,因為大家都戴口罩了,那個時候真的是最好的時代
Do you still remember the vulgar chief? You raised your hand, high school student, do you want to hurry up and put the second
各位還記得那位俗長嗎?你有舉手,高中生,你要不要趕快把第二次
right
對
If at that time someone told me there was no such thing
如果那個時候找人說沒有這樣子
and then to solve
然後去解決
I don't want to die
我不要還要死多少
At that time, the whole has really spread.
那時候真的是整個已經擴散開來
But let me add
不過我補充一下
this person is not important
這一個人不重要
the most important thing is each of you
最重要的是你們每一個人
Each of you has two body temperatures
你們每一個人都有兩體溫
There are measures to cooperate with the government
都有配合政府的措施
without the cooperation of the people
沒有全民的合作
this person has nothing
這一個人一點都沒有
but i really thank you
不過我真的是謝謝
The teacher also accepts this gift from me very much.
老師還特別受我這個禮物
Now I don't know how to speak
那現在就不曉得我該怎麼講話了
But we are very grateful
不過我們很謝謝
Professor Hong gave us a wonderful speech
紅教授給我們很精采的這個演講
Just what you told the classmates who watched us
就你同看了我們的同學講的
we have a lot of speeches
我們有很多的演講
this is deep for me
這個是對我深度
And everyone can understand
而且大家都能夠很了解
And then have a good understanding of Don
然後對於唐有一個很充分的了解
thanks again
我們再次謝謝
Professor Hong's speech to us
紅教授給我們的演講
Thanks
謝謝
you
you